music
音楽
problem
問題
ened
終わった
was
だった
steals
盗む
circle
丸
There is something important so he can't come
大事な用事があるので彼は来られない
Entrust me to help him host
彼のホストの手伝いを私に任せてください
So I'm a layman on the subject of today's phenomenon
したがって、私は今日の現象については素人です
If you say something wrong, please don't take effect
間違ったことを言ったら、それを実行しないでください
Everyone knows that the feast of knowledge is very important to this feast
知識の饗宴がこの饗宴にとって非常に重要であることは誰もが知っています
An important activity promoted by popular science knowledge
一般的な科学知識によって促進される重要な活動
I just saw an official document today
今日公式文書を見ました
The seventh feast of knowledge will gather and mature after the lecture
講義後に集い熟成する第七回の知の饗宴
The seventh is also about to run
第7回もいよいよ走り始めます
The first six are easily available at bookstores
最初の6冊は書店で簡単に入手できます
or where to find
またはどこで見つけるか
Welcome to go and have a look
ようこそ、見に行ってください
All we invite are inside and outside the courtyard
私たちが招待するのは中庭の内外だけです
very good experts
非常に優れた専門家や学者
Come and talk to us about the latest scientific developments
最新の科学開発について話しに来てください
we are very happy to have you today
今日はお会いできてとても嬉しいです
Institute of Atomic and Molecular Research, Academia Sinica
中央研究院原子分子研究所
The current director, Dr. Zhou Meiyin
現在の院長、周美音博士
Dr. Zhou came back from the United States in January this year
周博士は今年1月に米国から帰国した
Join Academia Sinica
加入中央研究院
Institute of Atomic and Molecular Sciences
原子分子科学研究所
Everyone knows that the Fate Institute is a very good fault of the Academia Sinica
運命研究所が中央研究院の大きな欠点であることは誰もが知っています。
Then it has a high status in the world
そうすると世界的にも地位が高くなります
So today he is going to talk about the latest development of nanomaterials
そこで今日、彼はナノマテリアルの最新の開発について話します。
Nano?
ナノ？
I only gradually heard the name in the late 1990s
1990年代後半から徐々に名前を聞くようになった
I remember once in the Legislative Yuan there was a legislator
かつて立法院に一人の議員がいたのを覚えている
The nanometer plan sent by the National Science Council seems to be worth one billion
米国科学会議が送ったナノメートル計画は10億の価値があるようだ
He said that this Taiwanese Penglai rice can't finish it
この台湾蓬莱米は食べきれないと彼は言いました
How much do you spend on Nano
Nanoにいくら使っていますか
so he is like me
だから彼は私と同じです
It was the first time I came into contact with nano
初めてナノに触れました
Nano NSA Program
ナノ NSA プログラム
Because I just remember people talking about Wikipedia
人々がウィキペディアについて話していることだけを覚えているからです
he didn't talk about nano
彼はナノについては話さなかった
So I also talked to that legislator
それで私もその議員と話しました
that legislator is famous
あの議員は有名です
I won't say who this is now
これが誰なのかは今は言いません
Then like him it was in the late 1990s
それから彼と同じように、それは1990年代後半でした
I just had a meeting and found out that there is this thing
ちょうど会議をしていて、こんなものがあることを知りました
Director Zhou graduated from the Department of Physics, National Taiwan University
周所長は国立台湾大学物理学科卒業
In fact, I know that Director Zhou is already very famous in National Taiwan University.
実際、周監督は台湾大学ではすでに非常に有名であることを私は知っています。
we have fantastic students
私たちには素晴らしい生徒がいます
He then went to the University of California
その後、カリフォルニア大学に進学
Ph.D. in Physics from Berkeley
バークレー校で物理学の博士号を取得
Then in Exxon
その後エクソンで
do this postdoc
これをポスドクしてください
Since 1989 in
1989年以来
Georgia Tech Institute of Technology
ジョージア工科大学
Professor of Physics
物理系教授
In 1998, he became a professor of politics
1998年に政治学の教授に就任
Then from 2005 to 2010
その後、2005 年から 2010 年まで
former department head
元部長
He was taken by us in January this year
今年の1月に我が家に連れて行かれました
Come back to take charge of the camp
キャンプの責任者として戻ってきてください
Director and Special Forces Researcher
所長兼特兵研究員
Especially the head of the State Council
特に国務院長官は
The director's main research field is
所長の主な研究分野は
Solid-state physics theory and first-principles calculations
固体物理理論と第一原理計算
Especially in the application of materials
特に材料の応用においては
director of incoming research
新任研究ディレクター
including various heels
さまざまなヒールを含む
nanosystem
ナノシステム
and solid scavenging materials
固体捕捉材
He was in the internationally renowned
彼は国際的に有名な
Rehabilitation has published more than 100 academic papers
リハビリテーション分野では 100 以上の学術論文が発表されています
Also had
もあった
country of america
アメリカの国
Science Foundation's President's Young Scholar Award
科学財団会長若手学者賞
and other important awards
およびその他の重要な賞
He is now a fellow of the American Physical Society
彼は現在、アメリカ物理学会のフェローです。
And served as the chairman of the American Physical Society for the distribution of computational physics
米国計算物理分布学会の会長を務めました
As I just mentioned, since the 1990s
さっきも言いましたが、1990年代から
Nano has become an important emerging field
ナノは重要な新興分野となっている
Many people, like me, thought that Nani and Penglaimi were the same thing in the 90s
多くの人は私と同じように、90年代にはナノと蓬莱美を同じものだと思っていました
Now I think no one knows no one knows
今は誰も知らないと思う 誰も知らない
And become part of the textbooks of elementary school, middle school and high school
小学校、中学校、高校の教科書にも採用される
This was unimaginable in our time
私たちの時代では想像もできなかったことでした
he is an elective
彼は選択制です
In the past 20 years in the development of nanoscience
過去 20 年間のナノサイエンスの発展
Carbon meter has a very important position
カーボンメーターは非常に重要な位置を占めています
The discovery and attention of carbon nanotubes, graphite, etc.
カーボンナノチューブ、グラファイトなどの発見と注目
is a very noteworthy thing
非常に注目すべきことです
Last year's Nobel Prize in Physics was awarded to two scholars who made major breakthroughs in the study of graphite
昨年のノーベル物理学賞は、黒鉛の研究で大きな進歩を遂げた2人の学者に授与された
two russian scholars
二人のロシアの学者
One of them came to the Central Plains to participate in the seminar shortly after winning the award
そのうちの1人は、受賞直後にセミナーに参加するためにセントラルプレーンズに来ました。
a very young man
とても若い男
Master is an expert in nanomaterials
マスターはナノマテリアルの専門家です
Today his topic is
今日の彼の話題は
carbon dimension official position
碳維也官職
Recent Developments in Nanomaterials
ナノマテリアルの最近の発展
I think this is a very interesting topic
これはとても興味深いテーマだと思います
The number of participants today is unprecedented
今日の参加者数は前例のないほどです
Everyone, after listening today
みなさん、今日聞いてから
It's just that nanometers are different from baked milk rice
焼きミルクライスとはナノメートルが違うだけです
We welcome the head of the seat
議席の先頭を歓迎します
the baking problem
ベーキングの問題
Thank you Vice President Wang
王副社長に感謝します
Thank you all for coming to this evening's discussion
今晩のディスカッションにお越しいただいた皆様、ありがとうございました
It's an honor to be with you all
皆さんと一緒にいられて光栄です
A little bit about the latest developments
最新の開発について少し
That's what Vice President Wang said
王副総統はこう言った
Nano this field
このフィールドをナノ化
It's been about the past ten or fifteen years
ここ10～15年くらいかな
there's been a lot of progress
たくさんの進歩がありました
So what I want to introduce to you today
そこで今日ご紹介したいのは
About the latest developments in nanomaterials
ナノマテリアルの最新の開発について
Parts related to carbon
カーボン関連部品
I think in this speaker I have noticed that
このスピーカーで気づいたと思います
we have some younger friends
私たちには若い友達が何人かいます
There are also some who are doing some more senior
もう少し上級の仕事をしている人もいます
friend here
ここの友達
So I think our speaker should not be too polite
したがって、私たちのスピーカーはあまりにも丁寧すぎるべきではないと思います
Yes, if you think there is something wrong
はい、何か問題があると思われる場合は
raise your hand anytime
いつでも手を挙げてください
Not much package
パッケージがあまりない
Because in some places, if you don't make it clear
場所によっては、明確にしないと
Can it affect the following
以下に影響を与える可能性がありますか
I don't mind saying that people want to be able to
人々ができるようになりたいと言うのは構わない
straighten things out
物事を正す
so feel free to ask questions
お気軽に質問してください
I think before we get to the subject
本題に入る前に考えます
Because the topic is nanoscience with carbon
炭素を使ったナノサイエンスがテーマなので
I want to start with a quick introduction
簡単な紹介から始めたいと思います
I think many of you have heard what nanoscience is
ナノサイエンスとは何かを聞いたことがある人も多いと思います
So let's say I have a quick definition on my side
それで、手元に簡単な定義があるとしましょう
That is, we hope to be able to discuss
つまり、議論できることを願っています
Or control because it is manipulate
あるいは操作だからコントロールする
at 1 to 100 nm
1～100nmで
properties in matter of this size or so
このくらいのサイズのプロパティ
What about nanometers in our
私たちのナノメートルはどうでしょうか？
In the more professional language
より専門的な言語で
Nano is actually turned upside down
Nanoは実際にはひっくり返されています
English is called Nano
英語ではナノと言います
so become nano
だからナノになる
It is the power of time
それは時間の力です
So if we talk about a nano
ナノについて話すなら
It is the rice to the power of time multiplied by time
時間×時間の米です
Nano means 100 centimeters
ナノとは100センチメートルを意味します
this size
このサイズ
at this length
この長さで
It's a way you can imagine
それは想像できる方法です
it's a very very very small unit
それはとてもとてもとても小さな単位です
Then in such a small place
そうすると、こんな狭いところで
Maybe we can see atoms
もしかしたら原子が見えるかもしれない
What about this length?
この長さはどうでしょうか？
properties of objects
オブジェクトのプロパティ
Many, many properties in the electronic properties
電子特性における非常に多くの特性
or mechanical properties
または機械的特性
or optical properties
または光学特性
chemical properties
化学的特性
have basically changed
基本的に変わった
that so
まあまあ
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
We can make some special definitions
いくつかの特別な定義を行うことができます
or special study
または特別な勉強
OK let it go
OK、放してください
sorry
ごめん
OK, so let me give you an analogy first
OK、それでは最初に例え話をさせてください
I just felt what nanometer is called
ナノメートルが何と呼ばれているかを感じました
We can imagine that the earth is so big
地球がとても大きいことが想像できます
OK then you have a small copper plate in your hand
OK、あなたの手には小さな銅板があります
OK, what about the two ratios?
さて、2 つの比率はどうでしょうか?
Like if say we shrink this down to
これを次のように縮小するとします。
A word of 1 meter and 100 centimeters
1メートル100センチの一言
Then this copper plate is called a nanometer
この銅板はナノメートルと呼ばれます
So we all know how big a copper plate is
銅板がどれほど大きいかは誰もが知っています
We probably all know how big the earth is
おそらく誰もが地球の大きさを知っているでしょう
It's their size difference
それは彼らのサイズの違いです
So you would imagine saying
だからあなたはこう言うことを想像するでしょう
where scientists can say
科学者が言えるところ
from such a large unit
あんな大きなユニットから
into such a small world
こんなに小さな世界に
Then you can see something in it
すると、その中に何かが見えます
to measure something
何かを測定する
Yes, I can say that it is not an easy thing
はい、それは簡単なことではないと言えます
You can imagine that on earth
地球上ではそれが想像できます
Let's say we're an alien
私たちが宇宙人だとしましょう
an alien
エイリアン
Come to Earth in a spaceship outside
外の宇宙船で地球に来てください
He wants to say you have a coin in your hand
彼はあなたが手にコインを持っていると言いたいのです
He wants to see what kind of words are written on the copper plate above you
彼はあなたの上の銅板にどんな文字が書かれているか見てみたいと思っています
You imagine it's a very, very difficult thing to do
それはとてもとても難しいことだと想像しているでしょう
He must have some special tools
彼は特別な道具を持っているに違いない
come down and see
降りてきて見てください
actually see what's on that copper plate
実際に銅板の上に何があるか見てみましょう
What are we going to do now?
どうしましょう？
in a lab the size of ours now
今の私たちと同じくらいの規模の研究室で
Able to enter a world of refugees
難民の世界に入ることができる
Then see how it arranges atoms one by one
次に、原子を 1 つずつ配置する様子を見てみましょう。
Then it has some form
そうすると、何らかの形があり、
now this
今これ
So this is our size above
これが上記のサイズです
So how will our situation change?
それでは、私たちの状況はどのように変化するのでしょうか？
This is a simple graph
これは簡単なグラフです
because mainly
なぜなら主に
Quantum Confinement
量子閉じ込め
It's a quantum-bound problem
それは量子限界の問題です
That is to say, if you assume a thing
つまり、何かを仮定すると、
Once restricted by the bureau
局によって規制されたら
limited words
限られた言葉
its nature will change
その性質は変わるだろう
You probably imagine a situation like this
おそらくこのような状況を想像するでしょう
For example, if in classical history
たとえば古典史なら
Let's look at a particle
粒子を見てみましょう
is a particle
粒子です
It bumped and bumped and this side is sealed
ぶつけてぶつけてこちら側は封印
We can see it running around like this in there
そこではこうやって走り回っているのが見えます
We can see a particle of this one object over there
あそこにこの物体の粒子が見えます
But in physics we have what's called quantum particle physics
しかし、物理学には量子素粒子物理学と呼ばれるものがあります。
It doesn't matter if you haven't heard the term
この用語を聞いたことがなくても問題ありません
I just want to mention the general things
一般的なことだけを述べたいと思います
That is to say, in quantum particle physics
つまり、量子素粒子物理学では、
a particle is not a particle
粒子は粒子ではない
It's actually a fluctuating cold tree
それは実は変動する冷たい木なのです
And then when it fluctuates or is blocked in the middle
そしてそれが変動したり、途中でブロックされたりしたとき
it will have different of these waveforms
これらの波形は異なります
Then each waveform represents that it has different energy
そして、それぞれの波形は異なるエネルギーを持っていることを表します
So this is a very, very superficial way of speaking.
したがって、これは非常に表面的な言い方です。
Then I think everyone probably has an experience
それなら誰もが経験があると思います
For example, you've probably all seen a violin, a cello, or a guitar.
たとえば、バイオリン、チェロ、ギターなどは誰もが見たことがあるでしょう。
when you want to change the sound
音を変えたいとき
You just change the length of the vibration of the string
弦の振動の長さを変えるだけです
right, according to different places
そう、場所によっては
When the length is changed, its frequency changes
長さを変えると周波数が変わります
Above Quantum Law
量子法則を超えて
its that frequency
その周波数です
The frequency of that wave content
その波の内容の周波数
is its energy
そのエネルギーです
So if we put a direction
それで方向性を定めるとしたら
so restrict later
だから後で制限する
it has changed a lot
大きく変わりました
that when we are in this
私たちがこの中にいるとき
What about the middle of this quantum confinement?
この量子閉じ込めの真ん中はどうなるのでしょうか？
can have different limitations
さまざまな制限がある場合があります
For example, we usually
たとえば、私たちは普段、
We are a three-dimensional space
私たちは三次元空間です
then we are in a certain area
それから私たちは特定のエリアにいる
One direction confines it
一方向に閉じ込める
We become a two-dimensional system
私たちは二次元のシステムになる
We call this two-dimensional nanomode
これを二次元ナノモードと呼びます
it is one piece
それはワンピースです
Nano means its thickness
ナノとは厚さを意味します
It's about a few nanometers
数ナノメートル程度です
Then if we say
それで、私たちが言うなら
If it is restricted in another direction
別の方向に制限されている場合
we'll see these
これらを見てみましょう
This is one-dimensional into nanowires
これはナノワイヤーの一次元です
This has both directions restricted
これには両方向が制限されています
If we are restricted in three directions
三方向に制限されたら
i become a thing
私は物になる
We are 0D
私たちは0Dです
GLD
GLD
0-dimensional nanoparticles
0次元ナノ粒子
In this case it's in our nanoscience
この場合、それは私たちのナノサイエンスにあります
see different systems
さまざまなシステムを見る
Then steal them they will belong to one of these
それからそれらを盗んでください、彼らはこれらのいずれかに属します
from zero to one to two
ゼロから１、２へ
What about the element carbon?
炭素という元素はどうでしょうか？
What I'll mention later is that
後で言及するのは、
It actually has all three
実はこの3つが全部揃っているんです
We'll see zeros like this
このようなゼロが表示されます
this is a nanosphere
これはナノスフィアです
Carbon is made up of carbon
カーボンは炭素からできています
This is a nanometer carbon tube
これはナノメートルカーボンチューブです
Each is a carbon atom or a binary
それぞれは炭素原子または二元原子です
This is the graphite west we want to mention today
これが今日お話したいグラファイトウェストです
The so-called Graphene
いわゆるグラフェン
It is a dual system
デュアルシステムです
That's so wait a minute we'll all be back to this
それはちょっと待ってください、私たちは皆これに戻ります
in each case i will mention
それぞれの場合に言及します
where are we in nanoscience
私たちはナノサイエンスの世界にいます
I want to clarify it again
もう一度明確にしておきたい
because it is a basically an emerging
基本的には新興国なので
interdisciplinary science
学際科学
Because whether in chemical physics or biomaterials science
なぜなら、化学物理学であれ、生体材料科学であれ、
There are many engineering disciplines
工学分野はたくさんあります
We are all slowly getting in touch with this aspect.
私たちは皆、この側面にゆっくりと触れ始めています。
will also use some of the properties of nano
nano のプロパティの一部も使用します
come and go on some of us
私たちの何人かは行ったり来たり
That is to say, to learn and explore some of its features
つまり、その機能のいくつかを学び、探索することです。
It has some emerging material properties
新たな材料特性がいくつかあります
I probably want to wait for this
おそらくこれを待ちたいと思います
maybe mention an example or two
例を 1 つか 2 つ挙げるかもしれません
we study nanoscience
私たちはナノサイエンスを研究します
We also need to develop new measurement and control tools
新しい測定および制御ツールを開発する必要もあります
into what I just said
私が今言ったことに
we're going to a very small place
私たちはとても小さな場所に行きます
If you can measure something very accurately
何かを非常に正確に測定できれば
There are many tools that must be developed
開発しなければならないツールがたくさんあります
Then Nano can now also be applied to some
その後、Nano はいくつかの用途にも適用できるようになりました。
health care energy or electronics
ヘルスケアエネルギーまたはエレクトロニクス
Some technology and design above electronic science
電子科学を超えたテクノロジーとデザイン
these are in progress
これらは進行中です
Then usually we are in this nano
そして通常、私たちはこのナノの中にいます
inside the field
フィールドの中
very important also
とても重要なことも
it takes a lot of time
とても時間がかかります
is to understand the interaction between matter
物質間の相互作用を理解することです
especially in such a small
特にこんな小さいところでは
in that length
その長さで
What about this whole science?
この科学全体はどうなるのでしょうか？
still in development
まだ開発中です
We have several practical application strengths
当社には実用的なアプリケーションに関するいくつかの強みがあります
wait might mention it
待ってくださいそれについて言及するかもしれません
most research and development projects
ほとんどの研究開発プロジェクト
still in progress
まだ進行中
I think what you can expect is to say
あなたが期待できるのは次のようなことだと思います
The future is in five or ten years
未来は5年後か10年後だ
You will continue to hear that
これからもそれを聞き続けるでしょう
There are many new applications of nano
ナノメートルの新しい用途は数多くあります
or nano
またはナノ
that emerging technology
その新興テクノロジー
in development
開発中
So this is a very simple generalization
これは非常に単純な一般化です
How will nanotechnology affect our lives?
ナノテクノロジーは私たちの生活にどのような影響を与えるのでしょうか?
I'm just starting out here and I want to use a couple of examples
ここで始めたばかりなので、いくつかの例を使用したいと思います
This is not directly related to the carbon we are talking about today.
これは、今日私たちが話している炭素とは直接関係ありません。
But I think there are a few more interesting situations
しかし、もっと興味深い状況がいくつかあると思います
The first one is to say that this is already being done
1つ目は、これはすでに行われているということです
We all know that pitch first
私たちは皆、そのピッチを最初に知っています
Everyone knows that you take a peach
あなたが桃を食べることは誰もが知っています
That surface is furry, isn't it?
その表面は毛皮ですよね？
So for this thing, you drop a water on it
それで、これについては、水を垂らします
it won't stick
くっつかないよ
The water turned into pieces and slipped away.
水は粉々になって滑り落ちていきました。
Then we usually wear clothes
それから私たちは通常服を着ます
you go to something
あなたは何かに行きます
have a drink
一杯やります
What you are most afraid of is that the drink is spilled on you
一番怖いのは飲み物をこぼされること
then get naked
それから裸になる
if there was a way to say something to you
あなたに何か言う方法があるとしたら
As soon as these liquids are sprinkled on
これらの液体を振りかけるとすぐに
become like this ball
このボールのようになる
and then go away like this
そしてこのまま去っていく
won't get it wet
濡れないよ
that's not a very good thing
それはあまり良いことではありません
If you sprinkle it, you will pat it
振りかけると撫でる
it just shoots and it goes away
ただ撃って消えていくだけ
I wouldn't say that I stained that dress.
私があのドレスを汚したとは言いません。
So now there are some techniques that say
そこで今では、次のようなテクニックがいくつかあります。
We can use 10 nanometer
10ナノメートルも使える
The carbon one that is so long
こんなに長いカーボンのやつ
that little kind of fiber
あの小さな繊維
What about this kind of thing?
このようなことはどうでしょうか？
It will be the same as the cotton fiber in our place
当店の綿繊維と同じになります
that is to say it fits together
つまり合っているということです
In this way, on this surface
このようにして、この表面上で
formed
形成された
Like our pick a peach on the surface
表面に桃を取った私たちのように
that furry
あの毛むくじゃらの
Except you can't see that furry now
今はその毛皮が見えないことを除いて
because that thing is so small
あれはとても小さいので
In such a situation
このような状況では
it will generate say on this surface
この表面上で発言権を生成します
those with some very small air
空気が非常に少ないもの
with those on these fibers
これらのファイバー上のものと
there will be one separated
一つは別れるだろう
So when those liquids fell on top
それで、それらの液体が上に落ちたとき
It turns into a ball like this
こんな感じでボール状になります
and you'll be gone
そしてあなたはいなくなる
things already done
すでに終わったこと
called fancy pants
ファンシーパンツと呼ばれる
This is called stain resistance
これを防汚性といいます
just won't stain
ただ汚れないだけ
that's something that's been done now
それはもうすでに行われていることです
Of course, what is the real principle behind the application here?
もちろん、ここでのアプリケーションの背後にある本当の原理は何でしょうか?
It’s just a lot of things that Lu Yuan can’t see now.
今のルー・ユアンには見えないものがたくさんあります。
very small inside
中はとても小さい
carbon fiber
カーボンファイバー
fibers that can be compared with cotton
綿繊維
can be held together tightly
しっかりとまとめることができる
Of course, this is what we want if we say
もちろん、私たちがこう言うなら、これが私たちが望むことです
Do many, many dives with a very powerful baggage machine
非常に強力なバゲッジマシンを使って、たくさんのダイビングをしましょう
Then the surface will inevitably come off
そうなると必然的に表面が剥がれてしまいます
slowly it will get wet
ゆっくりと濡れていきます
wet some of these features
これらの機能の一部を湿らせます
The basic principle of this design is
この設計の基本原理は、
is to imitate
真似することです
the surface of our peach
私たちの桃の表面
Let's see if those fluffy ones can do it
あのふわふわした奴らがそれができるかどうか見てみましょう
man-made structures
人工構造物
What about another example?
別の例ではどうでしょうか？
This is probably now probably a
これはおそらく今ではおそらく
Compare a Vision of Yuancheng
元城のビジョンを比較する
hope it can be done
それができることを願っています
That is to say, we take the very small particles of Nimi
つまり、ニミの非常に小さな粒子を取り出します。
What we call Nano-crystal is a very small crystal
私たちがナノクリスタルと呼んでいるものは非常に小さな結晶です
The four particles of ordinary people are Cadence Selenite, which is a composite
普通の人々の4つの粒子は、複合材料であるケイデンスセレナイトです。
it's very very it has some special properties
それはとてもとてもそれはいくつかの特別な特性を持っています
That is to say, when it reaches very small particles
つまり、非常に小さな粒子に到達すると、
like we can follow its size
その大きさを追うことができるように
Then it has different levels of different energies
そして、それは異なるレベルの異なるエネルギーを持っています
So in this is a photo just say
それで、この写真はただ言うだけです
If we shine a light on it and it shines some ultraviolet light
ライトを当てると紫外線が当たる
after absorbing the light
光を吸収した後
it has different energy levels
さまざまなエネルギーレベルがあります
so it shines
だから輝く
The colors of these radiances are based on the difference in energy levels
これらの光の色は、エネルギーレベルの違いに基づいています。
The years are determined by size
年はサイズによって決まります
So in this is an experiment just say
これは実験です
If placed in some agriculture
どこかの農業に置かれたら
Then shine these dead lights
そして、これらの死んだ光を輝かせてください
Then you will find that it has different colors
そうすると、色が違うことがわかります
so according to the color
だから色に合わせて
You know what size it is
サイズはわかりますか
That kind of example is very small
そのような例は非常に少ないです
Now someone is thinking about saying
今誰かがこう言おうと考えている
Because this thing can hear the human body
こいつは人間の体の声を聞くことができるから
can penetrate many things in your studies
勉強で多くのことを理解できる
So and it superficially can
したがって、表面的には可能です
we can put some antibodies on it
抗体を付けることができます
put something that is not external
外部にないものを入れる
Then it can carry the body of this station
そうすればこのステーションの本体を運ぶことができます
walk through school
学校の中を歩く
that this is an experiment
これは実験だということ
Let's say it puts some
いくつか入れたとしましょう
These antibodies antibody
これらの抗体抗体
It interacts with proteins emitted by certain IC packets
特定の IC パケットによって放出されるタンパク質と相互作用します。
They serve the function
それらは機能を果たします
So after it enters the human body
なので、人間の体内に入った後は
it goes where it likes
それは好きなところに行きます
with those proteins
それらのタンパク質を使って
When we take these little nanometers for example
これらの小さなナノメートルを例にとると、
to the female part of the animal
動物のメスの部分に
In the vicinity of inflammatory needle cancer cells
炎症性針状癌細胞の周囲
it just stays there
それはただそこに留まるだけです
If so
もしそうなら
If we shine another UV light outside
外でまた紫外線を当ててみると
Then the light is absorbed by it
すると光はそれに吸収されてしまいます
Then you start to shine over there
そうすればあなたはそこで輝き始める
so this is an experiment
これは実験です
experiment with mice
マウスを使った実験
Then it will also be able to detect
そうすれば検出もできるようになります
where the cancer cells are
がん細胞はどこにあるのか
So this is of course what to do in the future
もちろんこれは将来的にすべきことです
Hope to use this technique
このテクニックを活用したいと考えています
It can be said that there are these detections of this cancer
このがんにはこれらの検出があると言えます
Tell me where the cancer cells started to grow
がん細胞が増殖し始めた場所を教えてください
So of course it's a very long term one
もちろんそれは非常に長期的なものです
hope to achieve something
達成することを願っています
Also this is
これも
This is relatively new
これは比較的新しいものです
a result of last year
昨年の結果
That is what we call artificial skin
それが人工皮膚と呼ばれるものです
artificial skin
人工皮膚
we shine in our skin
私たちは肌で輝いています
has a very important special function
非常に重要な特別な機能があります
that is
あれは
You can feel it when you touch it
触ればわかるよ
right
右
Because we feel pressure after we touch it
触れた後に圧力を感じるから
So if say
それで言うなら
We're going to take an artificial skin
人工皮膚を採取してみます
you have to touch to put pressure
圧力をかけるにはタッチする必要があります
what about stress
ストレスはどうですか
to convey
伝えるために
words expressed by some signals
何らかの信号によって表現される言葉
you have to amplify those signals
それらの信号を増幅する必要があります
and then with some current
そして電流を流して
convey it
それを伝える
So when people study and say
ですから、人々が勉強して言うとき、
What to do when taking photos of these artificial skins
人工皮膚の写真を撮るときはどうするか
It actually uses some
実際に使用しているものもあります
Zoomed out here are some rice noodles
ズームアウトするとビーフンが見えます
Here
ここ
Because of rice noodle it has some functions
ビーフンだからいくつかの機能がある
That is, it can be used as an electrolytic body
つまり電解質体として使用できる
it amplifies a signal
信号を増幅します
So in a layer
つまり、ある層では
It bought a lot of rice noodles
ビーフンをたくさん買いました
Then these artificial skins
それからこの人工皮膚は
it is very it can bend
とても曲がることができます
Then it can have a layer on top of that
その後、その上にレイヤーを置くことができます
something that detects stress
ストレスを感知するもの
and pass that signal down
そしてその信号を伝えます
Then use this rice noodle
それならこのビーフンを使ってください
Send out the signal of this current
この電流の信号を送り出す
so we know
だから私たちは知っています
So measure the pressure everywhere
だからどこでも圧力を測定してください
so this is a
これは
can now
今出来る
a situation that does
そうなる状況
Then it needs that very low voltage to operate
動作するには非常に低い電圧が必要です
Sometimes you need other systems
場合によっては他のシステムが必要になることもあります
May require a lot of voltage
多くの電圧が必要になる場合があります
so not ideal
理想的ではありません
So how many
それで何個
There are several applications of this
これにはいくつかの応用例があります
after our course
私たちのコースの後
I want to spend the next five to ten years
これから5年、10年を過ごしたいと思っています
You will still hear a lot of new things coming out
まだまだ新しいものがたくさん出てくるでしょう
OK
OK
All right
わかった
ok now let's get back to the topic
さて、本題に戻りましょう
Let's talk about the role that look plays in this nanoscience
このナノサイエンスにおいて見た目が果たす役割について話しましょう
OK
OK
if you still
まだなら
Probably everyone should have heard of the periodic table of the elements.
おそらく誰もが元素の周期表について聞いたことがあるはずです。
right
右
Look at the elements
要素を見てみよう
Here
ここ
it is there
それはそこにあります
Its atomic sequence is six
その原子配列は 6 です
There are twelve electrons
電子は12個あります
right
右
it's not a metal
それは金属ではありません
It's right on top of the Sircum department
サーカム部門の真上にあります
that they have the same
彼らも同じものを持っているということ
very similar electronic structure
非常によく似た電子構造
There are many, many on our planet
私たちの地球上にはたくさんのものが存在します
inside our body
私たちの体の中に
big pile
一大堆胎
eat every day
毎日食べる
fetal water compound
胎児水配合物
then physically
それから物理的に
all those molecules
それらすべての分子
A lot of them contain fetal atoms
それらの多くには胎児性原子が含まれています
Then our entire organic chemistry
それでは私たちの有機化学全体が
It's the fluid element
それは流体要素です
That 20% of the human body is actually fetal atoms
人体の20％は胎児の原子である
but the fetal atom it is a
しかし、それは胎児の原子です
kaleidoscopic elements
万華鏡のような要素
because it has many
たくさんあるから
it can do many, many things
たくさんのことができます
We take the fetal atom out like this
胎児の原子をこのように取り出します
put it together
一緒に置く
It wants it to form very different images
非常に異なるイメージを形成したいと考えています
Everyone knows the first diamond
誰もが知っている最初のダイヤモンド
diamond is tire
ダイヤモンドはタイヤです
In fact, fetal element is in it
実は胎児の要素が入っている
or stone wood
または石材
It's still the black one in the pencil
まだ鉛筆の黒い部分です
That's a tire
それはタイヤです
placenta
胎盤
Those two are completely different situations
この二つは全く異なる状況です
that's inside the nami structure
それはナミ構造の中にあります
placenta will be formed
胎盤が形成されます
I can even mention Naimi's carbon
ナイミのカーボンについても言及できます
it is spherical
それは球形です
or carbon nanotubes
またはカーボンナノチューブ
And now the latest material
そして今、最新の素材
graphite west it is a flat
グラファイトウェスト、それはフラットです
There are already two
すでに2つあります
Liu Boer talked about a chemistry
劉伯爾氏は化学について語った
carbon nanospheres
カーボンナノスフィア
then one is physical
それから 1 つは物理学です
Said it was last year's graphite west
去年のグラファイトウェストだったって
I'll put this over here later
後でこれをここに置きます
Let me talk about it a little bit
それについて少し話させてください
so our
だから私たちの
now everyone's
今はみんなの
just like that
まさにそのように
What about carbon?
カーボンはどうですか？
In fact, in our
実際、私たちの中では、
that nano
あのナノ
Inside the Science of Nanotechnology
ナノテクノロジー科学の内部
actually very very important
実はとてもとても重要
Member of Parliament
議員
then let's go back first
それなら最初に戻りましょう
look at this
これを見てください
diamond and graphite
ダイヤモンドとグラファイト
let's get to know
知りましょう
it is at
それはです
our kind
私たちの種類
before going to nano
ナノに行く前に
what kind of properties will it have
どのような性質があるだろうか
If you have taken chemistry in high school
高校化学を履修している場合
I don't think anyone is unfamiliar with this
これを知らない人はいないと思います
because in carbon
カーボンだから
we usually talk about that
私たちはいつもそれについて話します
when the electronic structure
電子構造が
We have two different energy levels
私たちには2つの異なるエネルギーレベルがあります
Then this is our tree feather
それでは、これが私たちの木の羽です
Then there are 2S and 2P
あとは2Sと2Pですね
An A4 and P
A4とP
two different tracks
2つの異なるトラック
that in its ground state
基底状態にあるもの
The ground state is the lowest energy situation
基底状態はエネルギーが最も低い状態です
We have to consider four electrons outside
外側にある4つの電子を考慮する必要があります
So these two are in the track of A4
つまり、この 2 つは A4 のトラックにあります
The remaining two are in the P orbital
残りの2つはP軌道にあります
So this is the lowest energy
つまり、これが最低のエネルギーです
But since the two are quite close
でも二人はかなり近いので
so sometimes
だから時々
it goes to a higher level
それはより高いレベルに行く
a comparatively excited state
比較的興奮した状態
Then move the electron up again
次に電子を再び上に移動させます
One on A4 and three on P
A4に1枚、Pに3枚
So in this case
したがって、この場合には
the two of them will
二人はそうするだろう
probably mixed up
おそらく混ざっている
we are called
私たちは呼ばれています
In chemistry it is called hybridization
化学ではハイブリダイゼーションといいます
put the two together
2つを一緒にする
that becomes four together
それは一緒に4つになります
called SP3
SP3と呼ばれる
if four together
4人一緒なら
If we paint this out
これを塗りつぶしたら
A4 is usually a spherical
A4は通常球形です
It is directional, up, down, left, right, front, back
方向性はあります、上、下、左、右、前、後ろ
So when added together like this
したがって、このように合計すると
The hybrid orbiton of sp3 has a directionality
sp3の混成軌道には方向性がある
Then this directionality means
すると、この方向性が意味するのは、
There are four outside the middle one
真ん中の外に4つあります
So if this is the case
したがって、これが事実であれば
In the formation of the structure of most so-called diamonds
ほとんどのいわゆるダイヤモンドの構造の形成において
That is to say, any climbing atom
つまり、登る原子はどれも
There are four climbing atoms nearby
近くに登る原子が 4 つあります
Then this structure is a very, very stable
この構造は非常に安定しています
then very very
それからとてもとても
That is to say, it will not be accepted by outsiders
つまり部外者には受け入れられない
a structure of interference
干渉の構造
that's very very strong
それはとてもとても強いです
That kind of chemistry is made up here
そんな化学反応がここで生まれる
the structure like this
このような構造
That is, it is in our visible light
つまり、それは私たちの可視光の中にあります
It does not absorb visible light
可視光を吸収しません
So let's say we see transparent diamonds
それで透明なダイヤモンドが見えます
and then the whole thing is very, very hard
そして全体がとてもとても大変です
because it's hard to compress it
圧縮するのが難しいので
so it's just
だからそれはただ
Because of its arrangement
そのアレンジメントのせいで
and because of it this
そしてそのせいでこれ
the number of electrons it has
持っている電子の数
and decided to say that a physical property of it like this
そして、その物理的性質は次のように言うことにしました
of course this
もちろんこれ
This is the distance between its atomic rulers
これは原子定規間の距離です
Of course it's small
もちろん小さいですよ
Also on the Nano side
ナノにもあります
Calculated in temperature nanometers
温度ナノメートルで計算
so this is in
それでこれは入っています
Because of this arrangement
この取り決めのせいで
Put Taiyuan Quality Sauce Together
太原品質のソースを合わせて
it turns into a diamond
それはダイヤモンドに変わります
If we say we are too primitive
私たちが原始的すぎると言ったら
another arrangement
別のアレンジメント
becomes
になる
turned into stone membrane
石膜になった
become the stuff in our pencils
私たちの鉛筆の材料になる
Also Taiyuan
太原も
But what?
でも何？
We when we got to this house to stimulate the tires
タイヤを刺激するためにこの家に着いたとき
i don't take it all
私はそれをすべて受け入れません
Three plus three and four all put together
3 プラス 3 と 4 をすべて組み合わせる
I take the top and take two
私はトップを取って2つを取る
Take one here and turn it into SP2
ここから 1 つ取り出して SP2 に変えてください
Then leave the other one there
それからもう一つはそこに置いておきます
no matter where it is placed
どこに置いても
It does not interact with others by itself
それ自体は他の人と対話しません
If you make it like this
こうやって作ったら
SP2 is an S is an original
SP2はSですオリジナルです
What about the other two P's?
残りの2つのPはどうなるのでしょうか？
One is horizontal and the other is heavy
1つは水平で、もう1つは重いです
So to combine it becomes one
だから組み合わせると一つになる
called sp2 becomes an angle of 120 degrees
sp2と呼ばれる角度は120度になります
so it you turn things 120 degrees
それで物事を120度変えると
Then line up the words
次に単語を並べます
It's a Ginger like this
生姜はこんな感じ
It has three per atom
原子ごとに 3 つあります
it's in the booth atom it to the neighborhood
それはブースにあります、近所に送ってください
Then they form an angle of 120 degrees
次に、それらは120度の角度を形成します
a plane like this
このような飛行機
line it up
並べて
Because we live in a three-dimensional space
私たちは三次元空間に生きているので、
So all matter is three-dimensional
つまり、すべての物質は三次元である
If they are lined up, they will become the graphite kilometer stars we are talking about.
並べると、我々が話しているグラファイトキロメートルスターになります。
In fact, there are stalls inside
実は中に屋台もあるんです
everything is the same
すべてが同じです
So the complete foundation is built according to its arrangement
したがって、完全な基礎はその配置に従って構築されます
Its electronic structure will be different
電子構造が違うだろう
And on this plane
そしてこの飛行機では
Its layer-by-layer effects are very weak
レイヤーごとの効果は非常に弱いです
Most of the strong action is on this plane
強力なアクションのほとんどはこの次元で行われます
So it's a very soft thing
だから柔らかいものなんだよ
We can use it as kilometers
キロメートルとして使用できます
you write on paper
あなたは紙に書きます
why does it get out on paper
なぜそれが紙に残るのか
Because the relationship between them is too light
二人の関係が軽すぎるから
So the layers will peel off
そうすると層が剥がれてしまいます
That's why it has properties like this
だからこそこのような性質があるのです
This is what we see in these
これがこれらの中で見られるものです
matter that existed
存在した事柄
something in nature
自然界の何か
That's the nano world
それがナノワールドです
we have to make it
私たちはそれを達成しなければなりません
Rearrange these electrons from scratch
これらの電子をゼロから再配置します
The only possibility is
唯一の可能性は、
The whole nature has only two kinds
自然全体には2種類しかない
SP2 is arranged in a plane like this
SP2はこんな感じで平面に配置されています
Or like that diamond we just saw
あるいは、今見たばかりのダイヤモンドのように
This is an arrangement of measurements
これは測定の整理です
In fact, only these two
実はこの２つだけ
So let's say that in this
この場合、次のようにしたいとしましょう
throughout the development
開発全体を通して
Now this is 1996
さて、これは 1996 年です
in the lab
研究所で
there are three scientists
科学者が3人います
They made a new one
彼らは新しいものを作りました
The quest for materials called nanometers
ナノメートルという物質の探求
basically
基本的
take sixty atoms
原子を60個取ります
put it together
一緒に置く
Then form a structure
次に構造を形成します
like a ball like this
このようなボールのように
The so-called Buddy ball
いわゆるバディボール
what about this thing
これはどうですか
the football we all know
私たち全員が知っているサッカー
Take a football and have a look
サッカーを持って見てください
it's the exact same thing
それは全く同じことです
We are at this time when everyone is doing football
私たちは今、誰もがサッカーをしている時期です
have found that
それを見つけました
This way you can make a spherical thing
こうすることで球状のものを作ることができます
let's look at this thing
これを見てみましょう
you will find that say
そう言うのが見つかるでしょう
how to see it here
ここで見る方法
This side is a hexagon
こちら側は六角形です
That black place is a pentagon
あの黒いところは五角形です
Then each dot is a bomb atom
すると、それぞれの点が爆弾原子になります
So for any bomb atom
つまり、どんな爆弾原子についても、
it has three bomb atoms next to it
隣に爆弾原子が3つある
Live because
生きるから
flat time
フラットタイム
each is three
それぞれ3つです
So everyone is equal
だからみんな平等なんだよ
when you hear this
これを聞くと
if i were to bend it down
もし私がそれを曲げていたら
i must have a place
私には場所がなければなりません
less than six
6未満
so just
これだけ
It's all pentagonal
全部五角形だよ
so you can go back and get
それで戻って手に入れることができます
If you are interested, you can take a picture yourself
興味のある方は自分で写真を撮ってみてはいかがでしょうか
this is a quest
それはクエストです
then at this time
それではこの時に
When everyone is doing it in the lab
研究室でみんながやってるときに
It's just a picture bar that puts a bunch of suns together
それはたくさんの太陽を集めた単なるピクチャーバーです
formed between them
彼らの間に形成された
found a special structure like this
このような特殊な構造を発見しました
Then a structure like this is a new form
そうすると、このような構造は新しい形です
Because everyone thinks that
みんなそう思ってるから
we never saw this thing
私たちはこれを見たことがありません
Thought we made it in the lab
研究室でできたと思った
This was in the 90s
これは90年代のことでした
By the time of 2000, two thousand years
2000年までに2000年
There are many, many applications
たくさんのアプリケーションがあります
You have done a lot of research
たくさんの研究をしてきましたね
that last year
去年のこと
only found out in astronomy school
天文学学校でのみ発見されました
Possibly far, far away in outer space
もしかしたら遥か彼方の宇宙で
inside these nebulae
この星雲の中で
Discovery of a nebula 6,000 light-years away
6000光年離れた星雲を発見
Maybe something like this already existed at that time
もしかしたら当時からこういうものは存在していたかもしれない
That's why I found out
それでわかったんです
This stuff maybe not that we hear
このようなことは私たちが聞いたことではないかもしれません
first made
初めて作った
a structure like this
このような構造
What kind of a property will there be
どんな物件があるんだろう
why they won the nobel prize
なぜ彼らはノーベル賞を受賞したのか
to make something like this
このようなものを作るには
because yes it is very very
はい、それはとてもとてもですので
very very strong first time
とてもとても強い 初めて
Because these chemical circles are not easily broken
この化学円は簡単には壊れないので
So basically the ball is very stable
基本的にボールは非常に安定しています
very stable ball
非常に安定したボール
Ordinary people please imagine
普通の人は想像してみてください
This surface can attach some
この表面にはいくつかのものが付着する可能性があります
many other things
他にもたくさんのこと
For example, the molecules of some drugs
たとえば、ある種の薬物の分子は、
can put it on top
上に置くことができます
Then everyone was imagining at that time that
そのとき誰もが想像したのは、
I can put this thing in my studies
これを勉強に取り入れることができます
It can take things to where you tell it to deliver
届けるように指示した場所に物事を運ぶことができます
because this is small
これはとても小さいので
it doesn't work with anything else
他のものでは機能しません
Then it might be able to cross those cell membranes
そうすれば細胞膜を通過できるかもしれない
or some places
またはいくつかの場所
So for something like this is equal to a unit
したがって、このようなものは単位に等しいです
we can bring
私たちは持っていくことができます
Just say Manupay
マヌペイって言ってください
use it to do
それを使って行う
do something
何かをする
That is about after this discovery
それはこの発見後のことです
late 90's
90年代後期
or 10 years ago
あるいは10年前
That stuff is pretty, really hot
それはかなり、本当に熱いです
everyone told him
みんなが彼に言いました
this is a new thing
これは新しいことです
we all have to think about it
私たち全員がそれについて考えなければなりません
what kind of that thing can we use
それは何に使えますか
It can be found that it has some functions
いくつかの機能があることがわかります
or for special applications
または特殊な用途向け
so this is the first
これが最初です
Judgment-related refugee structure
判決に関連した難民構造
what about later
後はどうですか
Next step
次のステップ
What we found was that
私たちが見つけたのは、
We can use the structure just like that
この構造をそのまま使用できます
not make a ball
ボールを作らない
i can make him a pipe
彼をパイプにしてあげてもいいよ
roll it up
巻き上げて
make a pipe
パイプを作る
When making pipes like this
このようなパイプを作る場合
depends on how you roll
転がり方次第
have different directions
異なる方向性を持っている
So after that we have some terms
その後、いくつかの条件があります
this is called
これは呼ばれます
pull towards CZAC like a chair
椅子のようにCZACに向かって引っ張ります
That is to say, in a different direction
つまり違う方向に
their nature will be different
彼らの性質は違うだろう
some will be semiconductor
一部は半導体になるだろう
Some will be very conductive
非常に導電性の高いものもあります
So if say we take a
それで、たとえば、
A carbon nanotube
カーボンナノチューブ
And what about these
そして、これらについてはどうですか
It can go to the surface to absorb some
表面に行って一部を吸収する可能性があります
other molecules
他の分子
Then we can go and measure these conductivities
次に、これらの導電率を測定してみましょう
Then those molecules change the conductivity
すると、それらの分子が導電率を変化させます。
So these carbon nanotubes
つまり、このカーボンナノチューブは、
can become a
になれる
become a sensor
センサーになる
That is to say very sensitive
つまり非常に敏感です
some can go to measure some
測りに行く人もいる
A tool for other molecules
他の分子のためのツール
and at the same time
そして同時に
We also made some
私たちもいくつか作りました
Flight Panel Display
フライトパネルディスプレイ
The screen you made
あなたが作った画面
Everyone has to make it thinner and thinner
みんなでどんどん薄くしていかなきゃいけない
Then use less power
その後、消費電力を減らします
What about carbon tubes?
カーボンチューブはどうでしょうか？
It's actually a good material
実は良い素材なんです
it can be released in some of the
の一部でリリースされる可能性があります
The release of electrons under voltage has many effects
電圧下での電子の放出は多くの影響を及ぼします
It is said that some electronic companies are already making such products
一部の電子企業はすでにそのような製品を製造していると言われています
So this has only had two covers in the past
つまり、これは過去に2回しか表紙がありませんでした
This is our first science magazine
これは私たちの最初の科学雑誌です
Usually there are many, many articles about these stamina probes for a while
通常、しばらくの間、これらのスタミナプローブに関する非常に多くの記事が存在します。
So this was probably before this 2010
つまり、これはおそらく 2010 年より前のことでした
to every scientific federation
あらゆる科学連盟へ
Lots and lots of discussion about this material
この資料についてはたくさんの議論が行われました
These are the words that probably speak to us
それはきっと私たちに語りかけてくる言葉
It's already the first wave
もう第一波だよ
In 2006 five or six years ago
5、6年前の2006年に
Everyone started to find out
誰もがそれを発見し始めました
In addition, there is another thing
さらに、もう一つあります
This is what I've been looking for
これが私が探していたものです
The so-called graphite west
いわゆるグラファイトウェスト
This piece of stuff is taken out of the graphite
この部品はグラファイトから取り出されたものです
Then it will be a very good two-dimensional nanostructure
そうすれば、非常に優れた二次元ナノ構造になります。
That's because it's only one atom thick
それは原子1個分の厚さしかないからです
So if other probes that we see like this nano
したがって、私たちが見ている他のプローブがこのナノのようなものであれば、
or probe
またはプローブ
In fact, it is to take this part to roll up
実はこの部分を巻き上げるのです
or wrap it up like this
またはこのようにまとめます
Or we take layer by layer what we call graphite
あるいは、グラファイトと呼ばれるものを層ごとに取ります
So this is something that people are looking for
これは人々が探しているものです
Probably hope to be able to separate it
おそらく分離できると思います
Then I hope to be able to use it for another goal I want to achieve
そして、それを私が達成したい別の目標に使用できることを願っています
Then we call a structure like this Graphene
このような構造をグラフェンと呼びます
As far as graphite is concerned, it has SP2 as we just mentioned
グラファイトに関する限り、先ほど述べたように SP2 があります。
So the angle of each of them is 120 degrees
したがって、それぞれの角度は120度です
Remind me like this again
もう一度このように思い出させてください
The Graphite West Phenomenon Since 2004
2004 年以降のグラファイト ウェスト現象
Everyone has the first article introduction
誰もが最初の記事の紹介を持っています
For example, say that I can do this
たとえば、これができるとします
This is the paper that everyone will publish in the future
これは将来みんなが出版する論文です
Papers published worldwide
世界中で出版された論文
So you can see that this increase is unwilling to rise
したがって、この増加は上昇する予定がないことがわかります
So this trend is pretty pretty amazing
この傾向はかなり素晴らしいです
this paper daily paper
本紙日刊紙
You can imagine that there are many students
学生が多いことが想像できます
Or a researcher working in a lab for a few months
または、数か月間研究室で働く研究者
Then take this result and write it out
次に、この結果を取り出して書き出します
I finally wrote a paper
やっと論文書きました
In the past few years has been in this
ここ数年はこれにありました
This is a Xinjiang with more than a few thousand
ここは数千人以上が暮らす新疆ウイグル自治区だ
Eight thousand papers have come out
8000の論文が出てきた
But many, many people from different fields
しかし、さまざまな分野から多くの人々が
all wanting to find in it says
そこから見つけたいと思っている人は皆こう言う
there's something in here
ここに何かがある
We can research and use it on my topic
私のテーマで研究して使用できます
So throughout the development
したがって、開発全体を通して
in a column
コラムで
He just said something like this
彼はちょうどこんなことを言いました
他說Graphic Mentor to be Lady Gaga of Materials
彼は、グラフィックのメンターはマテリアルズのレディー・ガガだと言いました
say that for the material
材料のためにそれを言う
it's possible
それが可能だ
It's a goddess, everyone knows why
それは女神です、その理由は誰もが知っています
like this he said
このように彼は言いました
seems to be from
からのようです
It seems to come from nowhere
どこからともなくやってくるようだ
He came out of nowhere
彼はどこからともなく現れた
Then
それから
everyone is talking about him
みんなが彼のことを話している
Then what
じゃあ何
not long
長くない
He is going to be absolutely everywhere
彼は絶対どこにでもいるよ
you are not eating
あなたは食べていません
see him everywhere
どこでも彼を見かけます
so we all the world
だから私たち全員が世界中で
I see this news everywhere
このニュースをあちこちで見かけます
So for now
だから今のところ
This is a
これは
That is to say, many, many researchers
つまり、非常に多くの研究者が
found some special
特別なものを見つけました
special subject
特別な主題
the whole
全体
the whole trend
全体の傾向
The whole phenomenon started in 2004
この現象全体は 2004 年に始まりました
that's the first paper
それが最初の紙です
these two
この二つ
is now the first two
今は最初の 2 つです
The first two were taken later
最初の2枚は後で撮ったものです
These two Nobel Prize winners
この二人のノーベル賞受賞者は
British scientists
イギリスの科学者
Then this place this article
それではこの記事をここに置きます
is talking
話しています
This thing is actually a transistor thing
実はこれ、トランジスタなんです
他說atomic to the thing carbon films
彼は炭素膜のことを原子だと言いました
everyone understands this
誰もがこれを理解しています
which means it's very, very thin
つまり、非常に薄いということです
It is a two-dimensional thin film
二次元の薄膜です
He said he separated it
別れたって言ってた
Why can't I get it?
なぜ手に入らないのですか？
That's mainly because it mentions one thing here
それは主に、ここで 1 つのことに言及しているからです
That is to say, this article confirms that
つまり、この記事は次のことを確認しています
We can use it as a material for transistors
トランジスタの材料として使えます
Everyone knows that transistors are a very important
トランジスタが非常に重要であることは誰もが知っています。
on electronic circle
電子サークルで
important things
大事なこと
I'll talk about it later
それについては後で話します
Why do you think this is
これはなぜだと思いますか
Will do transistor material
トランジスタ素材をやります
will be so so so important
とてもとても重要になるでしょう
Then it is here to say
それならここで言いたいのは
they found out
彼らは知った
This can be used as a feel effect transistor
フィールエフェクトトランジスタとして使用可能
Then it can be used with
その後、それを使用できます
It can do some switch
何らかの切り替えができる
that is, the one that changes it
つまりそれを変えるもの
The thing that replaces the charged particles inside
中の荷電粒子を置き換えるもの
can have a great function
素晴らしい機能を持つことができます
and the reason it won the prize
そして受賞理由
because it
なぜならそれは
Can be equal to a new field of innovation
新しい分野のイノベーションに相当する可能性がある
they mean
彼らは意味します
words displayed
表示される単語
This thing has big, big potential
これには大きな可能性がある
Then they are the first to be able to
そうすれば、彼らが最初にできるのは、
able to make the first measurement
最初の測定を行うことができます
It's actually a very, very simple experiment.
これは実際には非常に単純な実験です。
Everyone thinks that physicists need very complicated and complicated instruments to do experiments.
物理学者が実験を行うには非常に複雑で複雑な機器が必要であると誰もが考えています。
or to do
またはすること
In this experiment it is actually very simple
この実験では実際には非常に簡単です
That is to say, after this article comes out
つまり、この記事が出た後、
In fact, many, many laboratories can
実際、非常に多くの研究室では、
do this next
次にこれをしてください
In fact, this lab in many schools
実際、この研究室は多くの学校にあります
also started to be able to make it out
も出せるようになってきました
Because the procedure in this lab is actually very simple
このラボの手順は実際には非常に簡単なので、
Of course now slowly everyone wants to take that
もちろん今はゆっくりと誰もがそれを受け入れたいと思っています
The system is getting cleaner
システムはますますクリーンになっています
there is a new way
新しい方法があります
OK
OK
Then see the dashboard
次にダッシュボードを見てください
Before I get to the following
以下に進む前に
because how to do this experiment
なぜなら、この実験のやり方は
This is a very interesting phenomenon
これはとても興味深い現象です
I usually show this to my students, which means
私は通常、これを生徒たちに見せます。つまり、
It will tell you how to do it on YouTube
YouTubeでやり方を教えてくれます
So what he did was simple
だから彼がやっていることは単純だ
get one of your tapes
テープを 1 つ入手してください
then you take a
それからあなたは
Pick out that pencil heart
鉛筆のハートを取り出してください
on top of the tape
テープの上に
You know the pencil has many, many, many layers in its heart
鉛筆の中心部には、たくさんの、たくさんの層があることはご存知でしょう。
Every floor is very close
どのフロアもとても近いです
usually you take a small one
通常は小さいものを使用します
There are about a few million layers in mm
mmで約数百万の層があります
But it doesn't matter, he just uses tape like this
でもそんなことは関係ない、彼はこうやってテープを使っているだけだ
don't want to be like
みたいになりたくない
inone to stick together and separate
くっついたり離れたりするもの
He is like saying that I have split several layers
彼は私がいくつかの層に分かれていると言っているようなものです
look like this
このように見える
really really really they do it
本当に本当に本当に彼らはそれをやる
can do some measurements
いくつかの測定を行うことができます
it's not fake
それは偽物ではありません
So he breaks up and repeats it several times
それで彼は別れてそれを何度か繰り返す
Every time he weighs it
彼が体重を量るたびに
Make it thinner without touching it once
一度も触れずに薄くする
at the end
最後に
It takes a piece of Silicon
シリコンの欠片が必要です
It's like something we use to make the bottom
底を作るために使うようなものです
put this thing on it
これをその上に置きます
scrape it off
それを削り取る
spread to the surface
表面に広がる
Then if you find the thinnest layer
次に、最も薄い層を見つけたら
The thinnest seems to be very close to transparent
一番薄いものは限りなく透明に近いようです
very thin very thin on top
非常に薄い 上部は非常に薄い
then remove
それから削除します
There is a little bit when it is removed like this
外すとこんな感じで少しあります
will stick to it
それに固執するでしょう
then put this thing
それからこれを置きます
get an optical microscope
光学顕微鏡を手に入れる
it's more complicated
もっと複雑です
This family does not have
この家族にはそれがない
to light microscope
光学顕微鏡へ
then go to
それからに行きます
Find an assistant for every college student in school
学校内のすべての大学生のアシスタントを見つける
you can find
発見できる
then just look for it
それからそれを探してください
Here is a thin
こちらが薄いです
Can't see clearly
はっきり見えない
because it's here
ここにあるから
it seems to be transparent
透明のようです
It seems that this place is opaque
ここは不透明なようだ
then carefully measure
それから慎重に測定してください
That's one or two layers
それは1層か2層です
shixi is there
シシーはそこにいる
So this is
それで、これは
when this thing comes out
これが出てきたら
Everyone thinks I can do it right now
誰もが今すぐできると思っている
I'll be able to take some measurements right away
すぐに計測してみます
So everyone this is a
それで皆さん、これは
It's like saying that it's a rare opportunity to say
滅多にない機会だと言ってるようなものです。
you can produce these things
あなたはこれらのものを生み出すことができます
At the beginning, these two people did this because they
最初、この二人がこんなことをしたのは、
to measure and they speak in Double
測定すると彼らはダブルで話します
so
それで
ok now
好 那現在
Why
なぜ
This is a
これは
an important breakthrough
重要な突破口
Because it seems so simple
とてもシンプルに見えるので
one by one
一個一片
one slice
一片
A membrane of a nanometer
ナノメートルの膜
something amazing
何かすごいこと
That's mainly because
それは主に次の理由です
in our electronics industry
私たちのエレクトロニクス業界では
everyone has heard
誰もが聞いたことがある
Selick
セリック
All our iPhones
すべての iPhone
everything inside the computer
コンピューター内のすべてのもの
now everything is
今はすべてがそうなった
made with fine
上質で作られた
That's an entire industry
それは業界全体です
since 1948
1948年以来
Then
それから
These transistors are
これらのトランジスタは、
was found out
発見されました
invented
発明した
Then what
じゃあ何
we were
私たちはいた
selected
選択された
The elements of drama are those of us
ドラマの要素は私たちです
these enemies
これらの敵
so we had
それで私たちは持っていました
Single Crystal is a single catty system
単結晶は1斤系です
principle we start mass manufacturing
原則として量産を開始します
Then this happened
それからこれが起こりました
invented these commercial
これらのコマーシャルを発明したのは
This is Pian Junking
ピアンジャンキングです
Some form of these transistors
これらのトランジスタの何らかの形式
and then in the next
そして次は
Birth of the collective line 1958
コレクティブラインの誕生 1958
It was many years ago
何年も前のことだった
But after this collective circuit is produced in this way,
しかし、このようにして集合回路が出来上がった後は、
we can mass
私たちは大量にできます
make things more and more complicated
物事をますます複雑にする
and then the features get better and better
そして機能はどんどん良くなっていきます
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
Then around 1965
それから1965年頃
There was a man named Gordon Moore
ゴードン・ムーアという男がいた
He made a statement
彼は声明を発表した
That is to say, he saw
つまり、彼は見た
The development of the whole manufacturing industry
製造業全体の発展
Then he predicted
それから彼は予言した
us transistors
米国のトランジスタ
Or these processors will get better and better
あるいは、これらのプロセッサはますます改良されるでしょう
Then his development trend is to say
そして、彼の発展傾向は次のようになります。
We are on a CPU in a
私たちはCPU上にいます
What are those on the component called?
コンポーネント上のそれらは何と呼ばれていますか?
Number of transistors
トランジスタ数
U.S.
私たち。
It is estimated that it will double every two years
2年ごとに2倍になると予想されている
doubles every two years
2年ごとに2倍になる
So it was painted from 1971 to 2001
1971年から2001年まで描かれたということですね
This is the number of our transistors
これはトランジスタの数です
You take one of our internal GPUs
当社の内蔵 GPU の 1 つを使用します
Inside the Central Process Unit
中央処理装置の内部
The number of transistors on your
上部にあるトランジスタの数
I can probably see it from behind. I can't see clearly
後ろからだと見えるかも知れませんがよく見えません
This is Painting 4
こちらは絵画4です
Everyone remembers that in 2001
誰もが2001年のことを覚えています
Painting 4 probably has
絵画 4 にはおそらく
It's about 10 million here
ここは1000万くらいだよ
Thousands of transistors are on it
何千ものトランジスタが搭載されています
on the latest computer
最新のコンピューターで
You see Painting 4
絵画 4 をご覧ください
The value of your computer has already arrived
あなたのコンピュータの価値はすでに現れています
A, say, a billion transistors on top of
たとえば、その上に 10 億個のトランジスタが搭載されている
So so many transistors have to be placed on it
非常に多くのトランジスタを配置する必要がある
Each must be functioning normally
それぞれが正常に機能している必要があります
your computer will be accurate
あなたのコンピュータは正確になります
no problem
問題ない
So in this situation
したがって、この状況では
You can find this thing is
これは
Getting smaller and smaller
どんどん小さくなっていきます
And what about this line
そして、この行はどうでしょうか
It is a
それは
our side is
私たちの側は
is not a Linear
線形ではありません
is a Lock-Rismick
ロックリズミックです
It's that Lock-Scale
それはロックスケールです
So if this is the case, it will always be double and double
そうなると、いつも2倍、2倍になります。
So if this is the case
したがって、これが事実であれば
Impossible to keep going up
上がり続けるのは無理
we are looking for
を探しています
in the fine element
細かい要素で
This thing is almost at a bottleneck
これはほぼボトルネックになっています
that's there
それはそこにあります
in such a development
このような展開の中で
This is actually a history of the twentieth century
これは実際には20世紀の歴史です
is a very very very special situation
非常に非常に特別な状況です
because you probably said
おそらくあなたが言ったから
We probably only buy computers
私たちはおそらくコンピューターだけを購入します
every year every two years
毎年2年ごとに
things are getting better
物事は良くなってきています
price did not increase
価格は上がらなかった
It's outdated after a year or two
1～2年経つと時代遅れになるよ
you can imagine you buy a car
あなたが車を買うことを想像することができます
We are twenty or thirty years from now
私たちは今から20年か30年後です
Your car's speed is about the same
あなたの車の速度はほぼ同じです
you never said
あなたは決して言いませんでした
There is room for improvement like this
このように改善の余地があります
so
それで
The result of that
この結果
that is
あれは
price has been
価格は
So the price of each Processor
したがって、各プロセッサの価格は
Per transistor cycle
トランジスタサイクルごと
you do the same buy the same
あなたも同じことをします同じものを買います
computer for the same money
同じお金でコンピューター
faster and faster
加速的に
more and more
だんだん
In 20, 30, 30, 40 years
20年、30年、30年、40年後
this is big
これは大きいです
for the progress of our species
私たちの種の進歩のために
The development of many things is very, very
多くのものの発展は非常に、非常に
the impact is very far-reaching
影響は非常に広範囲に及ぶ
Although with your mobile phone
携帯電話でも
Features in smartphones
スマートフォンの機能
is very advanced
非常に先進的です
about twenty or thirty years ago
二十年か三十年くらい前に
you need a big computer
大きなコンピューターが必要です
one does the same thing
一人は同じことをする
So say in
それで言ってください
such a progress
このような進歩
everyone will find out
誰もが知るでしょう
this can't go on
これは続けられない
So at that time everyone wanted to say
だからあの時みんなが言いたかったのは
is having a...
を持っています...
This just that Law
これはまさにその法律です
maybe...
多分...
one day will stop
いつか止まるだろう
why
なぜ
We do this when the current motor body is loose
現在のモーター本体が緩んでいるとこうなります
there will be many...
たくさんあるでしょう...
a lot of problems happen
多くの問題が起こります
Plus when you have so much stuff in there
それに、そこにたくさんのものが入っているときは、
When a lot of electrons are flowing around inside
内部に電子がたくさん流れていると
you generate a lot of heat
あなたはたくさんの熱を発生させます
lots of resistors
たくさんの抵抗
Then we'll have some
それでは、いくつかいただきましょう
the problems in these
これらの問題
then it's all over that
それならそれで終わりだ
The thickness of the Jetplasma
ジェットプラズマの厚さ
Then we can't put something
それでは何かを置くことはできません
keep shrinking
縮小し続ける
You also shrink to the end to get to the original
あなたも元に戻るために最後まで縮みます
So in an industry like this
ですから、このような業界では
Under such a big and such a big industry
こんなに大きな業界の下で
everyone is thinking
みんなが考えている
what to do next
次はどうする
so in
それで
So at this time everyone is
だからこの時はみんなが
I want to ask what is an alternative
代替品は何なのか聞きたいです
tie this element
この要素を結び付ける
because we almost
なぜなら私たちはほとんど
entire electronics industry
エレクトロニクス業界全体
It's just one industry in one department
それは 1 つの部門の 1 つの業界にすぎません
a lot of material
たくさんの材料
ever been considered
これまで検討されたことがある
like this is a
これは
A semiconductor of the so-called III-V group
いわゆるIII-V族の半導体
There are these different
こういった違いがあります
these elements
これらの要素
that they have some good properties
彼らにはいくつかの良い特性があること
There is something called this Mobility
このモビリティと呼ばれるものがあります
Mobility basically means
モビリティとは基本的には
when you test the voltage
電圧をテストするとき
how fast can your electron go
電子はどのくらいの速度で進むことができますか
you can imagine
想像できるでしょう
or its
またはその
its frequency
その周波数
that is to say it can make
つまり作れる
Those are the frequencies of the components
これらはコンポーネントの周波数です
That's what it uses
それが使われるものです
Might have some better effects
もう少し良い効果があるかも知れません
but these things are very rail
しかし、これらのことは非常にレールです
Then there are some problems
それからいくつかの問題があります
The middle insulator is hard to find
真ん中のインシュレーターがわかりにくい
at the same time
同時に
also thought of some
いくつか考えました
other bigger
その他の大きい
These semiconductors of BangGap
BangGapのこれらの半導体
those like
好きな人
Even the Diamond itself
ダイヤモンドそのものさえも
has also been considered
も検討されています
Of course they have their benefits
もちろんそれらにも利点はあります
we have some
いくつかあります
like ibm
像IBM
that was 몇 years ago
それは数年前のことでした
made a big investment
多額の投資をした
Then decided to say that there is no way to get a good product
それで、良い製品を手に入れる方法はないと言うことにしました
There's a downside to all these things
これらすべてにはマイナス面があります
That is not very cheap
それはあまり安くありません
then on production
それから生産中
If you want to grow a good body
綺麗な体を育てたいなら
it's not easy
簡単ではない
So in the entire electronics industry
つまり、エレクトロニクス業界全体で
Been trying to say we're looking for a new material
新しい素材を探していると言おうとしていた
new material
新的材料
So when this graphite west thing came out
それで、このグラファイトウェストのものが登場したとき
Everyone became very talkative
みんなとてもおしゃべりになりました
think it's a big thing
それは大きなことだと思う
then why
それでなんで
This incident started when we explored the museum in Nano
この事件はナノの博物館を探索したときに始まりました
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
it has a nice nature
それは素敵な性質を持っています
This nice property means that
この素晴らしい特性が意味するのは、
its
これは
For example, you take a copper wire or something
たとえば、銅線か何かを取ります。
you pass the current
あなたは電流を通過します
You're going to measure its resistance later
後でその抵抗を測定するつもりです
that's usually the longer words
それは通常、より長い単語です
The resistance will be larger
抵抗が大きくなる
Because electrons have to travel such a long route
電子は長い道のりを移動する必要があるため、
As for nanoprobes or other similar structures
ナノプローブまたは他の同様の構造に関しては
this is an experiment
これは実験です
That is to say, these conduction numbers and lengths
つまり、これらの伝導数と長さは
that's almost irrelevant
それはほとんど無関係です
is a flat one line here
ここは平らな一本の線です
means that I increase its length
それは長さを伸ばすことを意味します
I don't increase its resistance
抵抗力は上げない
Then this is a very, very good image
それから、これはとてもとても良い画像です
That is to say, its resistance is very small
つまり抵抗が非常に小さいのです
it doesn't lose much heat here
ここではあまり熱が失われません
The reason for this is in its electronic structure
その理由は電子構造にあります
In its SP2 arrangement
SP2 アレンジメントでは
Then there is a more advanced theory
次に、より高度な理論があります
to explain it in very physical terms
非常に物理的な言葉で説明すると
actually go figure it out
実際に行って調べてみる
I will not go through those for now
それでは、今のところはそれらを通過しません
Because it has something to do with some very interesting physical phenomena
それは非常に興味深い物理現象と関係があるからです
You can see it in this article where it says
この記事の中でそれを見ることができます。
It is notation and neutrino like particle
粒子のような表記とニュートリノです
It's those high energy ones
それはそれらの高エネルギーのものです
Some Particles in Ratvistic
ラトヴィスティックのいくつかの助詞
so it's in this
だからこの中にあるよ
some of it
それのいくつか
When the mathematical structure and that describe some properties
数学的構造がいくつかのプロパティを説明する場合
It has something to do with these
これらと関係があるのです
So for a physicist
つまり物理学者にとっては
it's an interesting material
興味深い素材です
Then there are some deep physics in it
そこには深い物理学が含まれています
how to calculate it how to understand its nature
それを計算する方法、その性質を理解する方法
What about practically?
実際にはどうですか？
It is a good electronic material
良い電子材料です
Then this time was when I was exploring the museum in Nano
そして今度はナノの博物館を探索していたときのことです
has been discovered
発見されました
That's just to say that nanometer exploration is not easy to master
それは、ナノメートル探査を習得するのは簡単ではないということだけです。
not working well
うまく機能していない
So when the two-dimensional space
したがって、二次元空間の場合、
The one with those British scientists in 2004
2004 年にイギリスの科学者が行ったもの
lab found
研究室が発見した
you can make this piece of stuff
あなたはこの作品を作ることができます
Like that video on YouTube I just had
先ほど持っていた YouTube のビデオのように
It is convenient for everyone to make it
誰でも作れて便利ですよ
Then everyone thinks
そうするとみんなが思うんです
this is a very very good trick
これはとてもとても良いトリックです
here in this one
ここにこれの
I guess it's probably the only place
たぶんここだけだと思います
you can see an equation stone
方程式石が見えます
So this is our structure
これが私たちの構造です
So this thing was actually in the 1940s
つまり、これは実際には1940年代のものでした
Everyone thought of it in the 1950s
1950年代には誰もが考えた
a theorist thinks
理論家は考える
If there is a thing like this
こんな事があったら
what kind of nature will it have
どのような性質を持つだろうか
At that time, I already counted some
その時はもう数えてた
the nature of this
これの性質
this is a picture
これは写真です
I draw here and this side is energy
ここに描くとこちら側がエネルギーになる
Here it actually says something like
ここでは実際に次のようなことが書かれています
momentum is momentum
勢いは勢いだ
electronic one
電子的なもの
Usually in any solid structure
通常、どのような固体構造でも
or inside the structure
または構造物の内部
We usually look at the so-called energy levels like this
私たちは通常、いわゆるエネルギーレベルをこのように見ます
The special place is in this part
特別な場所はこの部分です
Because this part of its energy and its momentum
なぜなら、この部分がそのエネルギーと勢いの一部だからです
There is a direct contrast between
間には直接的な対照があります
because we are in different
私たちは違うところにいるから
inside the usual electronics
通常の電子機器の内部
its
これは
Its engineering equation should look like this
その工学方程式は次のようになります。
In ordinary gene numbers, ordinary semiconductors
通常の遺伝子数では、通常の半導体
This is actually a
これは実際には
Momentum P-Square
モメンタム P スクエア
stored energy multiplied by 2
蓄積エネルギー×2
I think you think high school physics
高校物理だと思うよ
is the momentum squared
運動量の二乗です
Stored by mass multiplied by 2
質量×2で保存
will get your momentum
あなたの勢いを掴むでしょう
so it's basically the same thing
基本的には同じことです
But if this is the case
しかし、このような場合は
such a description
そのような説明
is a completely different one
全く別のものです
a structure of electrons
電子の構造
in such a nature
そんな自然の中で
so
それで
everyone has one
誰もが1つ持っています
understanding is
理解は
it is a very special substance
それは非常に特殊な物質です
then we are in
それから私たちはいます
You've probably heard one
おそらく聞いたことがあるでしょう
a term like this
このような用語
That is to say, it looks like this
つまりこんな感じです
A relationship of linear
直線的な関係
will get
取得します
here will get some
ここにいくつかあります
very different electronic structure
非常に異なる電子構造
so i think
だから私は思う
That's probably all I'm talking about here.
おそらく私がここで話しているのはこれだけです。
won't go down that
それは下がりません
If you are interested
もし興味があれば
If you are interested, we can discuss it again
ご興味がございましたら、またご相談させていただきます
its main benefit
その主な利点
It is the so-called Mobility that I just mentioned
先ほど申し上げたいわゆるモビリティです。
That is to say, after you add a voltage
つまり、電圧を加えた後、
How can electrons move freely?
電子はどのようにして自由に移動できるのでしょうか?
Still bumping into some big resistors
まだ大きな抵抗器にぶつかっています
That is for Graphene and Smootc
それはグラフェンとSmootc用です
We usually use a Mobility like this
私たちは通常このようなモビリティを使用します
something like this to represent
このようなものを表す
it is quite large
かなり大きいです
Usually Silicone is
通常シリコンは、
Like Graphene
グラフェンのような
This is probably more than
おそらくこれ以上です
Many, more than 100 times
多い、100回以上
So this is a very good property
ということで、とても良い物件です
This means that
この意味は
When our electrons flow here
私たちの電子がここに流れるとき
it's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
About a few microns
数ミクロン程度
The micron is about 10 of -6 when it is released
発売時のミクロンは-6の10程度
there will be a collision
衝突が起こるだろう
Its Linfree Path is how long it is
そのリンフリーパスの長さはどれくらいですか
How long does it take to collide
衝突するまでどれくらい時間がかかりますか
this is very long
これはとても長いです
So this is very important for making electronic components
これは電子部品を作る上で非常に重要です
very very good thing
とてもとても良いこと
so this matter
それでこの問題
Everyone has already measured such a number
誰もがすでにそのような数値を測定しています
Then I think it's a
それから私はそれはだと思います
A goal worth pursuing
追求する価値のある目標
Scientists all over the world are trying to find a way to say
世界中の科学者が次のように言う方法を見つけようとしています。
How do I grow the best form out
どうすれば最高のフォームに成長できるか
because we just saw that
ちょうどそれを見たばかりだから
you can be very simple
あなたはとてもシンプルでいいよ
use duct tape to get something out
ダクトテープを使って何かを取り出す
But the pollution inside
しかし内部の汚染は
It is not mass-manufacturable
大量生産はできません
The goal now is to say
今の目標はこう言うことです
how to make a like
いいねをする方法
It is very big in the silicon industry
シリコン業界では非常に大きな存在です
size
サイズ
capable of mass production
大量生産が可能
so everyone
だからみんな
many many laboratories
たくさんの研究室
now all are chasing
今はみんなが追いかけている
This is a
これは
a big one
大きなもの
A major goal to be recognized by all
誰もが認める大きな目標
Now this is about last year
さて、これは去年の話ですが
in 2010
2010年に
They can grow on metal surfaces
金属表面でも増殖する可能性がある
can grow to a
まで成長することができます
probably at
おそらく
you want this 0.2
これは0.2が欲しいです
millimeter
ミリメートル
this is so
これはとても〜です
so it grows to a fairly large
なのでかなり大きく成長します
A Grapin sheet
一個Grapin sheet
There are hundreds of micron in size
大きさは数百ミクロンあります
So I'm still searching
だから私はまだ探しています
so maybe i think in the past
だから多分私は過去にそう思った
next few years maybe
おそらく今後数年は
Sometimes I hear in the news that
時々ニュースで聞きますが、
so-and-so laboratory
どこぞの研究室
did something
何かをしました
that is likely to be with
それはおそらく一緒です
how do they make
彼らはどうやって作るのですか
how to produce
生産方法
think of a way to
～する方法を考える
find a good sample
良いサンプルを見つける
There is a way to mass-produce
量産する方法もある
There are many, many ways
たくさんの方法があります
One of them is of course
もちろんそのうちの1つは
Of course it doesn't mean to explain it.
もちろん説明するという意味ではありません。
they can grow on a
彼らは成長できる
related to semiconductor
半導体関連
像Silicon Carbide
像Silicon Carbide
How do you translate it in Chinese?
中国語ではどう訳しますか？
put on it
それを着てください
then heat
それから加熱します
Then the sucker runs away
すると吸盤が逃げ出す
the remaining carbon atom
残りの炭素原子
so it can grow to be different
そうすれば違うものに成長できる
On the Grapin of the different layers
異なる層のグラパンについて
that in such a long way
こんなに長い道のりで
has now started
今始まりました
got some results
いくつかの結果が得られました
So this just says
だからこれはただ言うだけです
results in last year
昨年の結果
Might be able to make some transistors out
トランジスタをいくつか作ることができるかもしれない
It's the size of 34mm
34mmのサイズです
probably grown to
おそらく成長した
a lot of that
それのたくさん
ten thousand of that
そのうちの1万
Transistors are now starting to do this
トランジスタはこれを実現し始めています
such a point
そのような点
So of course there is still a long way to go
もちろん、まだまだ道のりは長いです
But we slowly start
でも、ゆっくり始めます
it will be like this
このようになります
probably in the near future
おそらく近い将来
everyone can see say
誰もが見ることができます
some results came out
ある程度の結果が出てくる
certainly
そうです
people will ask
人々は尋ねるだろう
Our current computer is so good
私たちの現在のコンピューターは非常に優れています
so convenient
とても便利です
i do something every day
私は毎日何かをしています
Receive some emails directly
一部のメールを直接受信する
take a look online
オンラインで見てみる
I don't need that big function
そんな大層な機能はいらない
OK
OK
so nothing wrong
だから何も問題ない
This I think probably this thing is
これはおそらくこれだと思います
some things you will need later
後で必要になるいくつかのもの
compare special features
特別な機能を比較する
that special thing
その特別なこと
this is still
これはまだです
That is to say, common things still exist
つまり、共通のものはまだ存在します
then this may be another development
そうすると、これはまた別の展開になるかもしれない
That is to say, the development of computers with high performance and special functions
つまり、高性能で特殊な機能を持ったコンピュータの開発です。
It may be necessary to find some new materials to do this
これを行うには、いくつかの新しい材料を見つける必要があるかもしれません
so we'll see
それで、これは様子見です
maybe in the next few years
おそらく今後数年以内に
I know several big companies like IDM or
IDM や
What about Texas Instruments?
テキサス・インスツルメンツはどうですか？
Some of us are heavily invested
私たちの中には多額の投資をしている人もいます
Hope to be able to not lag behind in this field
この分野で遅れを取らないようにしたいと思っています
But there's still a lot of it
でもまだたくさんあるよ
scientific problems to be solved
解決すべき科学的問題
Now I want to summarize
それではまとめていきたいと思います
The graphite west area we just talked about
先ほど話したグラファイトウェストエリア
look at the atom
原子を見てください
It's the thinnest material we know of
私たちが知っている中で最も薄い素材です
because it's only one atom thick
原子1個分の厚さしかないから
then what about it
それならどうですか
Has great Electron Mobility
優れた電子移動度を有する
Its battery movement is pretty good
バッテリーの動きはかなり良いです
At least 100 times better than Silicone
シリコンより少なくとも100倍優れています
Now continue to improve the material may be even better
これからも改良を続けて素材はさらに良くなるかもしれません
And it's a very, very special material
また、非常に特別な素材です
because it has other features
他にも機能があるので
This Silicone is not available
このシリコンは入手できません
For example, its electrical conductivity is also very good.
例えば、導電性も非常に優れています。
so what happened to you hot
それで、あなたはどうしたのですか？
Let it go and you'll spread the word
それを手放してください、そうすればあなたはその言葉を広めることができます
this is a strange thing
これは奇妙なことです
It's very nice to have pine silver already metalized to heat
パインシルバーがすでに熱にメタライズされているのは非常に素晴らしいです
It puts silver 10 times better than silver
銀は銀よりも10倍優れています
so heat doesn't build up
熱がこもらないように
will spread
広がるだろう
Then it is also a strong
それならこれも強いですね
very strong material
非常に強い素材
Because their carbon atoms follow the carbon atoms
それらの炭素原子は炭素原子の後に続くため、
Chemicals are strong
化学物質は強いです
So it's also hard to tear it apart
なので引き裂くのも大変です
Usually we know that very strong materials
通常、私たちは材料が非常に強いことを知っています。
For example, steel
たとえば、鋼
He will be two hundred times stronger than him
彼は彼より200倍強いだろう
That is, if we pull it up
つまり、引き上げると
just put so much pressure
とてもプレッシャーをかけるだけ
he still won't break
彼はまだ壊れない
so he is a
だから彼は
On the other hand, it is also a strange
その一方で、不思議なことでもあるのですが、
have very special properties
非常に特殊な特性を持っています
Then this is physically and engineering
それから、これは物理的および工学的です
Compared with such considerations
そういった考察と比べてみると
But in chemistry
しかし化学では
We also found some very strange
非常に奇妙なものも見つけました
very special news
とても特別なニュース
Because it's a piece of this thing
それはこのものの一部だから
So we can put a lot of different
なので、いろいろなものを入れることができます
chemical molecule on top
上にある化学分子
then change its properties
次にそのプロパティを変更します
so many many chemists
とてもたくさんの化学者が
or the chemistry industry are doing different research
または化学業界は別の研究を行っています
wish to change its nature
その性質を変えたい
take say put some different molecules
たとえば、いくつかの異なる分子を入れるとします
put it on top
上に置きます
Adsorbed on it
それに吸着した
then change its properties
次にそのプロパティを変更します
at the same time on the optical
同時に光学的にも
This is the one I want to pursue now
これが私が今追い求めたいものです
It also has some optical properties
いくつかの光学特性もあります
we can use
私たちは使うことができます
Usually in this so-called
通常、このいわゆる
The one that SpinTronics uses that electron
その電子を使ったスピントロニクスのもの
Spin word spin above it has some
スピンワードスピンの上にいくつかあります
Those functions of magnetic
磁気のこうした働き
It is also very likely that there are some
いくつかある可能性も非常に高いです
The application space is inside
アプリケーションスペースは内側にあります
So this is why there are so many papers
だから論文がこんなにたくさんあるんだ
Because everyone will find different places in it
誰もがその中で異なる場所を見つけるでしょうから
do things differently
違うことをする
That many people now think of its application
今では多くの人がその応用を考えています
that in this thing is just in
このことの中にあることはちょうど
This is from that YTPD
これはYTPDからのものです
because everyone this place
みんながここにいるから
Everyone can put different things on it
誰もがさまざまなものを置くことができます
that can be found saying
それは言うことが見つかります
Let's say you cut it into a
それを にカットしたとしましょう
ribbon thing
リボンの事
In addition there is another
さらにもう一つあります
Give it another direction
別の方向性を与える
Confirmation is limited to
確認できるのは以下に限られます
you will find that say
そう言うのが見つかるでしょう
Hey, you can change some electronic structures
ねえ、いくつかの電子構造を変更できるよ
So this is called Natal Rehab
これはネイタル・リハビリと呼ばれるものです
So many laboratories are doing this kind of work now
現在、非常に多くの研究室がこの種の研究を行っています
Then it can do a
そうすれば、次のことができます
molecular gas detector
分子ガス検出器
You put different molecules on top
さまざまな分子をその上に置きます
you find it conductive
導電性があることがわかります
or those inductions
またはそれらの誘導
you can measure it
測定できます
Then of course we've seen
それからもちろん見てきました
Groger's Transistor
グロガーのトランジスタ
can already be made
すでに作ることができます
Integrate Circuit
その集積回路
Integrated circuits start slowly
集積回路の起動が遅い
You can put a lot of transistors on it
トランジスタをたくさん搭載できる
Then we saw that someone wanted to use it to do
その後、誰かがそれを次の目的で使用したいと考えていることが分かりました。
The function of that solar cell
その太陽電池の働き
Because it's something in this area
この地域のことだから
can make good electrodes
良い電極を作ることができる
Then some Bio-Device
それからバイオデバイス
Then found out that bacteria don't like
その後、細菌が嫌いであることがわかりました
This M-Pack Bacteria Stuff
このMパックバクテリアのもの
bacteria don't like this stuff
細菌はこのようなものを好みません
So you can consider saying
したがって、次のように言うことを検討できます
This can be done for applications in Bio-
これは、バイオのアプリケーションに対して行うことができます。
So after this thing comes out
だから、これが出た後は
All scientists develop independently
すべての科学者は独立して開発します
everyone's imagination
みんなの想像力
Then hopefully it will find that say
そうすれば、うまくいけば、それが言うことがわかります
how things would be different
物事がどう違うのか
can happen
発生する可能性があります
can create the one that will find various applications
さまざまなアプリケーションを見つけるものを作成できます
right
右
good
良い
Come again, I want to go back to the end
また来て 最後まで戻りたい
That is to say our original one of course
もちろん弊社オリジナルです
Morse that Roll
ロールを巻くモールス信号
let's go back to that
話に戻りましょう
I might go back to that picture just now
今すぐあの写真に戻るかもしれない
That is to say, this thing
つまり、このことは、
keep going up
上がり続ける
our e-sports
私たちのeスポーツ
On that CPU more and more
そのCPUでどんどん
computers are getting faster
コンピューターはますます高速になっています
that's possible
それは可能です
what about this line
この行はどうですか
This is Silicon's line
これはシリコンのラインです
Maybe it's going up all the way to the end and it will definitely hit HIT
もしかしたら最後まで上がって確実にHITするかもしれない
must reach this limit
この制限に達する必要があります
What about before reaching this limit?
この制限に達する前はどうでしょうか?
we can imagine
私たちは想像できます
Maybe change a thread or use another material
糸を変更するか、別の素材を使用する可能性があります
that could be the one
それかもしれない
The whole limit might be different
全体の制限は異なる可能性があります
that's what we want to do right now
それが私たちが今やりたいことです
Then Guo Renmu put this
それから郭仁夢はこれを置きました
when making this prediction
この予測をするとき
He also imagined that when
彼はまた、次のことを想像しました。
such a degree
その程度の
This is a so-called Explonational Growth
これはいわゆる爆発的成長です
But it just can't be Forever
でもそれは永遠には無理だ
So he finally proposed in 1965 that year after
それで彼はその翌年の1965年についにプロポーズした
in his 50 years
彼の50年間に
I put him in the last one
私は彼を最後に入れました
on his 50th anniversary
彼の50周年に
he mentioned
彼は言及した
No explanation is forever
いかなる説明も永遠ではない
it's impossible to go all the way up
ずっと上まで行くのは不可能です
but
しかし
Ok, Delay forever
オーケー、永遠に遅らせる
Just change that forever
それを永遠に変えるだけ
So everyone hopes to find new materials
だから誰もが新しい素材を見つけたいと思っています
be able to develop another way
別の方法で開発できる
I think a lot this time
今回はいろいろ考えます
Scientists in the world are now a goal to strive for
世界中の科学者が今、努力すべき目標となっています
Like I'm coming to an end today
今日も終わりに近づいているような
Then
それから
I'll see if you have any questions
ご質問がございましたら確認させていただきます
Thank you Director Zhou for your wonderful speech
周所長、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
we have a lot of time
私たちには時間がたくさんある
is there anyone here who can
ここにできる人はいますか
Ask Director Zhou
周監督に聞く
you just mentioned that
あなたは今それを言いました
Graphite sita is ten times better than winning
グラファイトシータは勝つより10倍良いです
Then I will ask Director Zhou
それでは周監督にお聞きします。
Is it possible that Moxi West can expect to win at all
そもそもモクシ・ウェストが勝利を期待できる可能性はあるのか？
The second question is
2番目の質問は
The cost of graphite west and the cost of winning
グラファイト・ウェストのコストと勝利のコスト
How much is the difference? Thank you
どれくらい違いますか?ありがとう
OK he's ten times better than winning
OK 他比贏好十倍
That's his thermal conductivity
それが彼の熱伝導率です
To win has his function
勝つことには彼の役割がある
Winning him is a very expensive thing
彼に勝つことは非常に高価なことだ
why is it expensive
なぜ高いのですか
because he's almost he's a precious metal
なぜなら彼はほとんど貴金属だから
he is not easy
他不容易
Not easy to oxidize, right?
酸化しにくいですよね？
like gold
黄金のように
Pure gold is also not easy to oxidize
純金は酸化しにくいのも特徴です
Feature Stick Metal
特徴 スティックメタル
it has its special form
それは特別な形をしています
Although the meaning of replacing the battalion is to say
大隊を交代させるという意味はあるが、
you may be in some
あなたもいるかもしれません
Let's say I need to be very thermally conductive
熱伝導性を高くする必要があるとしましょう
Of course we have some contacts
もちろん連絡先もあるよ
Where do you go in two years?
2年後どこへ行く？
Metal Has Its Benefits
金属には利点がある
it can melt with sweat
汗で溶ける可能性があります
Then glue it on like that
あとはこのように接着します
What is actually a two-dimensional thing
そもそも二次元とは何なのか
So it's only partially possible
だからそれは部分的にしか可能ではない
no way completely
まったくダメだ
cannot completely replace
完全に置き換えることはできません
because every material has
どの素材にもあるからです
The benefits of each material
それぞれの素材の利点
Give plastic the benefits of plastic
プラスチックにプラスチックの利点を与える
Glass has the benefits of porcelain
ガラスには磁器の利点があります
So we use it for something
それで私たちはそれを何かに使います
is the best place to use it
それを使うのに最適な場所です
That high thermal conductivity
その高い熱伝導率
have a comparative advantage
比較優位がある
For example, many of us
たとえば、私たちの多くは
you are in the computer
あなたはコンピューターの中にいる
Normally you would think this place
普通ならここだと思うだろう
The CPU is very hot
CPU的地方特別熱
next to
の隣に
Add a fan to send the heat out
熱を逃がすためにファンを追加する
sometimes you are opening to see
時々あなたは見ようと心を開いています
one place it has a copper shelf
一か所に銅製の棚があります
over there for heat dissipation
放熱のためにあそこにあります
So if you use something like graphite
したがって、グラファイトのようなものを使用すると、
It's no problem to dissipate heat.
放熱も問題ありません。
so it's a benefit
だからそれは利益だ
so it dissipates heat quickly
熱を素早く放散するので、
yes it will spread the heat
はい、熱が広がります
it will spread
それは広がるだろう
when it works by itself
それ自体が機能するとき
doesn't generate a lot of heat either
あまり熱も発生しません
because it's that
それはそれだから
great mobility
優れた機動性
so it doesn't say
だからそれは言わない
The heat is because we have resistance
暑いのは抵抗があるから
Resistance is where electrons pass through
抵抗は電子が通過する場所です
I'm about to collide with someone
誰かと衝突しそうになる
hit it hit it hit it
当たる、当たる、当たる
generate a lot of heat
多量の熱を発生させる
It has to go a long way before colliding
衝突するまでに長い距離を行かなければならない
So yes it's good here
はい、ここでいいです
Yes, there may be some possibilities in the future
はい、将来的には可能性があるかもしれません
Of course if we say good
もちろん良いと言えば
thermal conductivity
熱伝導率
then design these
次にこれらをデザインします
These heavy heads these electronic components
この重い頭、この電子部品
about to be redesigned
再設計されようとしている
Redesign him to take full advantage of his benefits
利点を最大限に活用するために彼を再設計する
Thanks
ありがとう
What about the second question?
2番目の質問はどうでしょうか？
his
他的
his cost
彼の費用
cost
料金
Cost is hard to say now
コストは今は何とも言えません
Because now
因為現在
us
私たち
you imagine this
あなたはこれを想像します
Silicone industry this industry
シリコーン業界 この業界
from
から
take off in the 60s
60年代に離陸する
until now
今まで
40 years 40 years 50 years this
40年、40年、50年、これ
decades down
数十年前
everything is already
すべてはすでにある
completely
完全に
developed
発展した
so
それで
For Smoji his
スモジのために
how to make the first
最初の作り方
Now
現在
Is it still in a stage of scientific research
まだ科学研究の段階ですか
Because we still want to find the best way
私たちはまだ最善の方法を見つけたいから
The cheapest way to manufacture in large quantities
最も安く大量に製造できる方法
and then made his
そして彼のものを作りました
the extent of his limit
彼の限界の程度
not too many impurities
不純物が多すぎない
So this is what we just mentioned
これが先ほど述べたことです
Scientists almost all over the world think that
ほぼ世界中の科学者は次のように考えています
It's a very, very clear goal
とてもとても明確な目標です
you know who can find a best way
誰が最善の方法を見つけられるか知っていますか
He may be the next number
彼が次のナンバーになるかもしれない
so he knows
だから彼は知っている
This is a very important topic
これは非常に重要なトピックです
Then if it can be solved
それで解決できれば
The impact on the future is very heavy
それは将来に多大な影響を与えるだろう
So in the end how expensive he will be
それで最終的に彼はどれくらい高価になるでしょう
or how
あるいはどうやって
now we have no idea
今は何も分かりません
because how is this
なぜなら、これはどうですか
Everyone is still playing
みんなまだ遊んでるよ
say who can find the best way
誰が最良の方法を見つけることができるか言う
So how much will it cost him?
それで、彼にかかる費用はいくらになるでしょうか？
we don't know now
今は分かりません
silver is expensive
銀は高価です
we know silver is expensive
私たちは銀が高価であることを知っています
so
それで
So it's hard to predict what the future holds
したがって、将来がどうなるかを予測するのは困難です
For example, you go back to 20 years ago
たとえば、20年前に戻るとします。
then someone tells you
そうしたら誰かがあなたに言います
you can hold a phone in your hand
電話を手に持つことができます
20 years ago there were mobile phones which were very big
20年前にはとても大きな携帯電話がありました
still on the car
まだ車の上にある
because of the contact
連絡のせいで
So now like this little phone
だから今はこの小さな電話のように
told you 20 years ago
20年前に言った
I have a call after you sign
サインした後に電話があります
You can also access the Internet
インターネットにもアクセスできます
At that time, I didn't know what the internet was
当時はインターネットというものを知りませんでした
So what will happen next?
それで、次に何が起こるでしょうか？
This is difficult for us to predict
これを予測するのは困難です
That's just to say that each of these research breakthroughs
つまり、これらの研究のそれぞれが画期的な進歩を遂げたということです。
will give us some new hope
私たちに新たな希望を与えてくれるだろう
in cash
現金で
The gap between graphite and rock
グラファイトと岩石の隙間
Now look at what kind of graphene
では、どのようなグラフェンなのか見てみましょう。
you can make it yourself from the account
アカウントから自分で作ることができます
or are you going to buy
それとも買うつもりですか
someone can grow
誰かが成長できる
There aren't many that are really on sale right now.
現在販売されているものはほとんどありません。
because everyone is developing
みんな成長してるから
Today I said I can sell you a little today
今日はちょっと売ってもいいって言ったのに
There is a new method coming out tomorrow
明日は新しい方法が発表される予定です
That is to say, there are constantly new
つまり、常に新しいものが存在するということです
Every month, you will see new papers coming out
毎月、新しい論文が発行されるのを目にします
i want to do this
これをやりたいです
It will take a while before we can decide who will eat it
誰が食べるか決めるまでにはしばらく時間がかかります
or what is the best way
または最善の方法は何ですか
Thanks
ありがとう
Watch the news slowly, maybe in the next few years, you will see some in the news
ニュースをゆっくり見てください。おそらく今後数年以内にニュースでいくつか目にするでしょう。
Said that agricultural scientists discovered something
農業科学者が何かを発見したと言う
Let what is related to the real ink system
実際のインクシステムに関係するものを教えてください
There should be a lot of news about this
これに関してはたくさんのニュースがあるはずだ
Thank you so much
どうもありがとう
Who
WHO
Ask Director Zhuo
朱監督に聞く
It is because of the Lanometer part
ラノメーター部分のせいです
In our natural world
私たちの自然界では
did it happen naturally
それは自然に起こったのか
I mean say for example
つまり、たとえば
Galaxy T
ギャラクシーT
Then we will develop to a certain point in the future
そして、将来ある時点まで発展するでしょう
our natural world
私たちの自然界
Because the industry has used a lot of Lanometer
業界ではラノメーターが多数使用されているため、
There is no way for nature to consume these things that come out
自然界から出てくるものを消費する方法はありません
Then if we prevent these phenomena
では、これらの現象を防げれば、
now a subject
今が主題です
means sell your stuff
自分のものを売るという意味
Is it harmful to the human body
人体に有害ですか
because you know small things can go through
小さなことでも通り抜けることを知っているから
So while some people do some research
それで、いくつかの研究をする人もいますが、
that is to say, what harm will
つまり、どんな害があるのか​​というと、
That thing is not very clear now
そのことは今はあまり明確ではありません
because something like
のようなものだから
Something like that Carbon-6-6-6
カーボン6-6-6のようなもの
not very reactive
あまり反応しない
It is not easy to reflect with many things
いろいろなことを振り返るのは簡単ではない
So the comparison probably won't do much harm
したがって、この比較はおそらく大きな害を及ぼさないでしょう
you are right
あなたが正しいです
Naturally, there are some like that nano-explorer
当然、ナノエクスプローラーのようなものもある
found out later
後でわかった
when it heats like this
こんなに暑いと
As far as everyone finds out, those who say black
誰もが知る限り、黒と言う人は
Inside those things
それらのものの中に
Maybe it was before
もしかしたら前にもあったかもしれない
It's just that people didn't find it
ただ人々がそれを見つけられなかっただけです
But more and more man-made examples of these nanometers
しかし、これらのナノメートルの人工の例はますます増えています
Of course, you have to be more careful what kind of elements you look at.
もちろん、どのような要素に注目するかにはより注意する必要があります。
At least for now there will be
少なくとも今のところは、
Haven't found a big big one that hurts
痛い大きな大きなものは見つかりませんでした
But this is in the engineering school
でもここは工学部です
about environmental engineering
環境工学について
This is a very important subject
これは非常に重要なテーマです
That is to say, considering the problem of environmental pollution
つまり、環境汚染の問題を考えると、
or harm to the human body
または人体に害を及ぼす可能性があります
This is something everyone is considering now
これは今誰もが検討していることです
a subject among some
何人かの主題
that said in nature
それは自然の中で言った
like i said far away
遠くで言ったように
There is actually that desire in my luck
実際、私の幸運にはその願望があります
it's surprising
それは驚くべきです
Maybe we've had it on Earth before
たぶん、私たちは以前にも地球上でそれを経験したことがあるでしょう
It's just that everyone didn't try to find it out.
ただ、誰もがそれを知ろうとしなかっただけです。
so
それで
I think a very short answer
非常に短い答えだと思います
Probably what I just said
おそらく私が今言ったこと
This is a subject currently under study
これは現在研究中のテーマです
It is also an important subject
それも重要なテーマです
What kind of harm will it do to humans?
それは人間にどのような害を及ぼすのでしょうか？
will it hurt
痛いですか
it's not clear yet
それはまだ明らかではありません
maybe for some elements
おそらくいくつかの要素のため
It is because some elements are more poisonous
一部の元素はより有毒であるためです
If it becomes endurance
我慢になったら
when it penetrates the skin or something
皮膚などに浸透する可能性がある場合
That may cause more damage
それだとさらに被害が広がるかもしれない
For charcoal
炭用
It compares if it doesn't work as well as others
他のものと同じように機能しないかどうかを比較します
then it might not be that big
そうしたら、それほど大きくないかもしれません
But this time Liu Dai said that scholars and experts should study it carefully.
しかし今回、劉岱は学者や専門家は注意深く研究する必要があると述べた
thank you for a very good speech
とても良いスピーチをありがとう
Two questions for Chief Zhou
周長官への2つの質問
the first one is very
最初のものはとても
A while ago HITC Superconductor was a very, very popular topic
少し前まで、HITC 超電導体は非常に人気のあるトピックでした
But then there are several technical problems
しかし、その後、いくつかの技術的な問題が発生します
Of course, the most important thing is that there is no way to mention three things and four temperature
もちろん、最も重要なことは、3 つのことと 4 つの温度について言及する方法はないということです。
if say
言うなら
If one day Superconductor ITC can be raised to room temperature
いつか超電導体ITCを室温まで上げることができたら
Which one do you think is more effective than this one?
これより効果的なのはどれだと思いますか?
or better
それ以上の
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question I want to ask is
私が聞きたい2番目の質問は、
Most of his people so far speak Electronics
これまでのところ、彼の人々のほとんどはエレクトロニクスを話します
Talk about the Golden one just now
今、ゴールデンについて話してください
If the Golden Model seems to be 2Dimension
ゴールデンモデルが2次元に見える場合
Have you thought about 3Dimension
3次元について考えたことがありますか
Use Optical and Transparent
光学的および透明なものを使用する
In fact, he only needs to add a Dimension
実際には、ディメンションを追加するだけで済みます。
He can increase quickly
彼はすぐに増えることができる
thousands of times millions of times
何千回も何百万回も
Is this another way to get around that limitation
これはその制限を回避する別の方法ですか
Thanks
ありがとう
OK
OK
very good question
とても良い質問
first question
最初の質問
Hitc superconducting high temperature superconducting
Hitc超電導 高温超電導
The benefits he wants to solve or can get
彼が解決したい、または得られる利点
not like this
こんなんじゃない
His main thing is that he just wants to fight
彼の一番の目的は、ただ戦いたいだけだということだ
will not say
言わないだろう
But it is not a
しかし、それはそうではありません
But semiconductors are not a
しかし、半導体はそうではありません
make that electronic component
その電子部品を作る
it can be used
使用できます
That is to say, some parts can also be used in the middle
つまり、一部のパーツは途中でも使用できます
make wires what?
ワイヤーを作りますか？
But it doesn't have the structure of these semiconductors
しかし、それはこれらの半導体の構造を持っていません
have these good qualities
これらの良い性質を持っています
This is what we need to make a
これが私たちが作る必要があるものです
Materials used to make a computer like this
このようなコンピューターを作るために使用される材料
That high temperature superconductor is now
その高温超伝導体が今
That is to say, there are some technical problems
つまり、技術的な問題がいくつかあるということです
after it reaches a certain stage
ある段階に達すると
just stop there
そこに止まってください
the temperature won't go up
気温が上がらない
Of course this means
もちろんこれはつまり
one suddenly has a breakthrough
突然突破口が開く
then stop there
それでそこで止めてください
many many years
何年も
Everyone can't find a way to break it
誰もがそれを打破する方法を見つけることができない
This will say to wait for the next wave
これは次の波を待つように指示します
Now a lot of people are finding new material
今、多くの人が新しい素材を見つけています
The temperature is not that high
気温はそれほど高くありません
But the more we learn about this substance
しかし、この物質について知れば知るほど、
We know better which direction to look for
私たちはどちらの方向を探せばよいのかをよく知っています
So there is no basis for this
だからこれには根拠がないんだよ
The two problems solved are different
解決される 2 つの問題は異なります
The two solutions are not the same
2 つのソリューションは同じではありません
that physically speaking
それは物理的に言えば
they are very
彼らはとても
Both are a very challenging
どちらも非常に挑戦的なものです
one of those subjects
それらの主題の1つ
That is, if someone can figure it out
つまり、誰かがそれを理解できれば、
This is
これは
That is to say, a very big contribution
つまり、非常に大きな貢献をしているのです
That
それか
Just the second question
2番目の質問だけ
so far
ここのところ
to this 2 reps
これまでの2回
2 reps
2回繰り返します
right
右
exist
存在
before this
この前に
while everyone is discussing that
みんながそれについて議論している間
When Morse Law
モールスの法則のとき
there is a direction
方向性がある
The transistor that walks in 3D
3Dで歩くトランジスタ
was that time
その時でしたか
And there are still some people
そしてまだ何人かいる
Continue to pursue making it 3D
3D化を追求し続ける
make it flat
平らにする
inside too
内側も
encountered some difficulties
いくつかの困難に遭遇した
That is according to the material
それは資料によると
You just mentioned another
先ほど別のことについて言及しましたね
That is to say, from the optical way
つまり、光学的な方法から
to interact with him
彼と交流するために
That's the direction everyone's been thinking about for many years.
それは誰もが長年考えてきた方向性です。
Because in the silicon base
シリコンベースなので
What we call optical electronics
私たちが光エレクトロニクスと呼ぶもの
we hope to have some
いくつかあることを願っています
Silicon can follow
シリコンは追随できる
Those laser beams or some optical ones
それらのレーザービームまたはいくつかの光学ビーム
some coupling
何らかのカップリング
which can then be put together
それから組み立てることができます
Not just conductive electronics come out
登場するのは導電性エレクトロニクスだけではない
Then follow this outside optical
次に、この外側の光学部品を使用します
The probes are somewhat associated
プローブはある程度関連しています
so that was a very
それはとても素晴らしいことでした
That is to say, a big subject
つまり大きなテーマ
many people are chasing
多くの人が追いかけている
It's just that at that time
ただ、その時は
silicon with
シリコン付き
Because it is it does not absorb light very well
光をあまり吸収しないので、
Because it is the so-called indirect gap
いわゆる間接ギャップだから
Its direct gap is relatively large
直接的なギャップは比較的大きい
its absorbing light
その吸収する光
this or that
これかそれか
It means about three or four ED
EDが3つか4つくらいということですね
will have a lot of absorption
吸収力が高いでしょう
So that's a really big specific
それは本当に大きな具体的なことです
That is how to follow
それがフォローする方法です
The Silicone Base Electronics
シリコンベースエレクトロニクス
with some of these Optical
これらの光学式のいくつかを使用して
can be combined
組み合わせることができます
This is many, many, many years of hard work
これは何年も、何年も、何年もの努力の積み重ねです
not yet fully achieved
まだ完全に達成されていない
So for Silicone
それでシリコンについては
This aspect is relatively weak
この側面は比較的弱いです
Of course, if you change to other materials
もちろん他の素材に変えても
maybe there is another possibility
もしかしたら別の可能性もあるかもしれない
This can have another
これには別のものがある可能性があります
Follow Optics and Electronics
光学およびエレクトロニクスをフォローする
can have a better combination
もっと良い組み合わせができる
So this is also in these semiconductor industries
これは半導体業界でも同様です
Some problems that everyone has been trying to solve
誰もが解決しようとしてきたいくつかの問題
It is also the direction of development
開発の方向性でもある
It's just that there are no good results yet.
ただ、まだ良い結果が出ていません。
total maintenance
トータルメンテナンス
this is
これは
i want to talk
話したい
has great usage
素晴らしい使い方があります
i think it's ok
大丈夫だと思います
i think we can
できると思います
think about it
考慮一下
we need to talk to us
私たちと話す必要があります
of this object
このオブジェクトの
Need to consult with us
要相談
Congratulations
おめでとう
That is to say before Bucky Bull was
つまり、バッキー・ブルが誕生する前ということです。
When carbon 60 came out
カーボン60が出てきた頃
In fact, he had many different applications at the beginning.
実際、彼は当初、さまざまなアプリケーションを用意していました。
But it doesn't seem to have seen anything yet
でもまだ何も見えていないようだ
practical application in life
生活の中での実用化
I don't know if he was later
彼が遅かったかどうかはわかりません
where did one meet him
どこで彼に会いましたか
the solution of development
開発の解決策
That's compared to Graphite Creek now
それは今のグラファイトクリークと比較されます
Is there any place for reference?
参考になるところはありますか？
Thanks
ありがとう
OK, the original carbon 60 because it is one by one
OK、オリジナルカーボン60ですので1本ずつです
So if you want to use
したがって、使用したい場合は、
I want you to find a way to get to the area
ケケ地区に行く方法を見つけてほしい
be able to use it to do something
それを使って何かをすることができる
and put it together or do
それをまとめるか、
OK Carbon 60 over there
OK カーボン 60 はそこにあります
In fact, it will be discharged into a solid carbon 60
実際には固体のカーボン60に排出されます。
Each unit is carbon 60
各ユニットはカーボン60
Then there are some nice properties in that
それから、そこにはいくつかの素晴らしいプロパティがあります
you can talk to another one
他の人と話すことができます
Echoline Metals to put in
入れるエコリンメタル
make some new some
いくつか新しいものを作る
image of object
オブジェクトのイメージ
But the real use
でも実際の使い方は
That is to say, one by one
つまり、一つ一つ
how are you going
調子はどうですか
how do you grab one to do something
何かをするためにどうやってそれをつかみますか
put it back
元に戻してください
This thing is more difficult
こっちの方が難しいよ
That graphite west side
あのグラファイトの西側
Everyone will feel a little hopeful
誰もが少しの希望を感じるでしょう
wish it was such a large piece of long
こんなに大きくて長かったらいいのに
grow out of the bottom
底から成長する
Then a large piece of it is produced in large quantities
そして、それの大きな部分が大量に生産されます
Then use some more from above
次に、上からさらに使用します
we have those now
私たちは今それを持っています
Lysograph's method to cut
リソグラフのカット方法
or make those three mouthfuls
またはその3口を作ります
it's easier this way
この方が簡単です
easier to make things
物事を作りやすくする
the shape you want
あなたが望む形
or whatever you want
またはあなたが望むものは何でも
because of the carbon talc stuff
カーボンタルクのせいで
You said you were going to grab one
一つ掴みに行くって言ってたよね
how do you catch
どうやって捕まえますか
such a small thing
そんな小さなこと
there's no way you can grab it with anything
何かを使って掴むことはできない
or to adsorb
あるいは吸着する
or you put it
それともあなたがそれを置きますか
At best, stick it to the surface
せいぜい表面に貼り付ける程度です
to make some control changes
コントロールを変更するには
Like that, so the above is a bit higher in terms of difficulty.
そんな感じで、上記は難易度的には少し高めです。
So if you really go
それで本当に行くなら
Is there really any good application for Greedy Stone?
本当にGreedy Stoneに適したアプリケーションはあるのでしょうか？
that might be in science
それは科学的にそうなのかもしれない
But it doesn't seem to say that it is made into a product
でも商品化されているとは言えないようです
It is a product of Tanyoushi.
丹洋紙の商品です。
i don't know if
どうか分からない
I'm not entirely aware of recent developments
最近の動向についてはまったく分かりません
So I can't talk about this place
だからこの場所については話せない
That's it
それでおしまい
At that time, Moxi was mainly because he combined the previous
当時、モクシは主に以前の機能を組み合わせたものでした。
everyone on this surface
この地表にいる全員が
The semiconductor industry is doing this on the surface
半導体業界はこれを表面的に行っている
how to grow film
フィルムの育て方
How to do these layer by layer
これらをレイヤーごとに行う方法
There is a lot of experience in this area
この分野では多くの経験があります
So his two-dimensional thing
だから彼の二次元のものは
He can be more easily controlled
彼はもっと簡単にコントロールできる
easy to set it up
簡単にセットアップできます
then become something
それから何かになる
Layer Shelf or Shera
レイヤーシェルフまたはシェラ
Or design some other structure
あるいは他の構造を設計する
it's easier stuff
それはもっと簡単なことです
Now the most important thing is to say
さて、最も重要なことは言うことです
how can you grow well
どうすればうまく成長できますか
and then be able to control it
そしてそれをコントロールできるようになる
can then be mass-produced
そして量産できるようになります
then also very cheap
それからまた非常に安い
It's not that there are only a few places where it can grow
成長できる場所が限られているわけではない
OK and then when it's over
OK、それが終わったら
you can understand its nature
その性質を理解することができます
Then redesign what kind of circuit you want
次に、どのような回路が必要かを再設計します
OK, the design
よし、このデザイン
Maybe it's not the same as before
もしかしたら前と同じではないかもしれない
Because of its electronic nature
その電子的な性質のため、
The electronic structure is different
電子構造が違う
ok so then what to do
わかった、それではどうするか
When it is possible to make a transistor
トランジスタが作れるようになったら
you put those oxides on it
あなたはその上にそれらの酸化物を置きます
or how are you going to do your
それともどうするつもりですか
get your electricity
電気を手に入れてください
Other different types of transistors
その他の異なるタイプのトランジスタ
So it still needs some
したがって、まだいくつか必要です
development over time
時間の経過に伴う発展
So the Norval value of this physics means
したがって、この物理学の正常値は次のことを意味します
We seem to have a
があるようです
There is a direction like this
こういう方向性もあるんですね
that can really make something
それは本当に何かを作ることができる
still take a while
まだ時間がかかります
not so fast
そんなに早くない
So this thing is
それで、これは
Just to say that now I seem to see a
ただ言いたいのは、今私が見ているようです
Seems like a pretty promising thing
かなり有望な事のように思えます
At least after trying many, many materials in the past
少なくとも過去に非常に多くの素材を試した後では
we may see there is a hope
希望があることがわかるかもしれない
Well, these are like a lot of US military
まあ、これらは多くの米軍に似ています
invested a lot of money
多額の資金を投資した
that's what this development says
それがこの展開が言うことだ
It is the kind of High-end is a special function
ハイエンドならではの特殊な機能です
Then some special electronic components
それからいくつかの特殊な電子部品
no you probably wouldn't say
いいえ、あなたはおそらく言わないでしょう
bring this price down so low
この価格をこんなに安くしてください
Because we are so computerized now
今はコンピューター化が進んでいるから
it's pretty cheap now
今はかなり安いです
also very very very
また、とてもとてもとても
Very powerful thing
非常に強力なもの
So the words of the general public
そこで一般大衆の言葉は、
still the one that lasts so long
それでもこんなに長く続いたのは
Silicon inter-suit will not disappear completely
シリコンインタースーツは完全に消えない
that just means we have another chance
それは、もう一度チャンスがあることを意味します
go find something better
もっと良いものを探しに行ってください
Thanks
ありがとう
Two questions. One is that the director just mentioned that
質問が２つありまして、１つは今局長がおっしゃいました。
There are three types of graphite, one is spherical, the other is tube and the other is flat
黒鉛には球状、管状、扁平状の3種類があります。
I would like to ask some of their physical properties in these three states
これら 3 つの状態における物理的特性についていくつかお聞きしたいのですが
For example, if I have a bunch, you don't have carbon balls to put together
たとえば、私が束を持っている場合、組み立てるためのカーボンボールはありません。
Then I use light, is it with a bunch of carbon tubes?
それからライトを使いますが、カーボンチューブの束でしょうか？
With lighting he has a different sheen or something
照明によって彼は違う光沢か何かを持っています
and their properties, for example, in the six bodies
およびその特性（たとえば、6 つの体）
Or is there any difference in physical properties such as conductive poison?
それとも導電毒などの物性の違いがあるのでしょうか？
Then there is the second question
それから2番目の質問です
That is, Norbell said that they used tape to layer graphite layer by layer.
つまり、ノーベル氏はテープを使ってグラファイトを一層ずつ重ねたという。
But when we were experimenting
しかし、私たちが実験していたとき、
We must control every thickness of him very precisely
私たちは彼のあらゆる厚さを非常に正確に制御しなければなりません
How to control the thickness of each layer in the laboratory
研究室で各層の厚さを制御する方法
Thanks
ありがとう
OK first question
OK 第一個問題
He's exploring the pavilion or the ball or the flat graphite
彼はパビリオンやボール、あるいは平らなグラファイトを探索している
Its electronic structure is different
電子構造が違う
For example, when graphite is a piece, it will reverse electricity
たとえば、黒鉛が破片になると、電気が逆になります。
Then if the carbon tube
それならカーボンチューブなら
Some carbon tubes are semiconductors
一部のカーボンチューブは半導体です
Some carbon tubes are metallic
一部のカーボンチューブは金属製です
That is, their resistance is relatively small
つまり、抵抗は比較的小さいです
depending on its direction
その方向に応じて
So that aspect can
したがって、その側面は、
Maybe it can be adjusted
もしかしたら調整できるかもしれない
Or you can tune different carbon tubes
または、別のカーボンチューブを調整することもできます
jump out that measure up
飛び出す
may be different
違うかもしれない
The energy level of the ball
ボールがそのエネルギーレベル内にある場合
That is to say, there is a gap
つまりギャップがあるということ
that is to say itself
つまりそれ自体
that is to say there is a
つまり、
energy gap on top
頂上のエネルギーギャップ
So it's big
だから大きいんだよ
so that
となることによって
So its properties are different
なので性質が違います
nature is different
性質が違う
That
それか
The second question just now is
今の２番目の質問は、
thickness
厚さ
How do you say to control it
それをコントロールするにはどうすればいいですか？
OK, yes
はい
You tell me two... actually there is no way to control
2つ教えてください...実際には制御する方法はありません
what to do is say
何をするか言うことです
Later, after many experimenters did this,
その後、多くの実験者がこれを行った後、
I made a lot of them
たくさん作りました
Then go to the Wangxue Well Weijing to find
次に、Wangxue Well Weijing に行って見つけます。
I see this seems to be two layers
なるほど、これは二層になっているようですね
There seems to be a layer
層がいるらしい
you go find students
あなたは生徒を探しに行きます
you are in a hurry to plan a lot of time
あなたはたくさんの時間を計画するために急いでいます
Just look for it bit by bit for a month
1ヶ月かけて少しずつ探してみてください
Look where it says it's a layer
レイヤーと書かれているところを見てください
I'm doing an experiment here
ここで実験をしています
so it's totally out of control
だから完全に制御不能だよ
what did you do
あなたは何をした
look for what you see
見えるものを探してください
Maybe you can't find this piece
もしかしたらこの作品が見つからないかもしれません
layer by layer that never
層ごとに決して
If this is expected, you can find it
これが予想される場合は、それを見つけることができます
If you find it, you can measure it.
見つかったら計測してみます。
So that's pretty much out of control
それはかなり制御不能です
After that, the more advanced method now
その後、現在はより高度な方法が
That is to say, if you can grow
つまり成長できれば
You can adjust the situation in the laboratory
研究室の状況を調整できます
one or two layers
1層または2層
but only later
でも後になってだけ
So it was just a
それで、それはただの
a very simple way
とても簡単な方法
there are some samples you can take some measurements
測定できるサンプルがいくつかあります
Then after taking measurements, it was found that
その後、測定を行ったところ、次のことが分かりました。
this seems
これはそうです
This is of good nature
これは善良な性格です
the whole can repeat
全体は繰り返すことができます
These things don't hit the nail on the head every time
これらのことは毎回うまくいくわけではありません
that's mainly for you
それは主にあなたのためのものです
Many, many labs can do the same thing
非常に多くの研究室が同じことを行うことができます
Those measurements that learn a lot can be repeated
多くのことを学ぶ測定は繰り返すことができます
Then everyone will believe
そうすればみんな信じるよ
this thing should be right
これは正しいはずだ
is such confidence
そんな自信ありますか
i want to ask two questions
2つの質問がしたいです
It's the first Smosh
初めてのスモッシュです
if you pull him a little bit
彼を少し引っ張ったら
Then some of his physical properties will change a lot
そうすれば彼の物理的特性のいくつかは大きく変化するでしょう
The second question is
2番目の質問は
Why is the Tan-60 called Lingwei structure?
Tan-60 はなぜ Lingwei 構造と呼ばれるのですか?
does he have a story
彼に話はありますか
if you pull
引っ張れば
His electronic structure will change
彼の電子構造は変化するでしょう
That's just saying someone weighed it down
それは誰かがそれを評価したと言っているだけです
Then his electronic structure
それから彼の電子構造
There may be a small one that can GaP will appear
GaPが出現する可能性のある小さなものがあるかもしれません
Of course it would take a lot of changes
もちろんかなりの変更が必要になるだろう
Only then will he change his atom-to-atom script
そうして初めて、彼は原子から原子へのスクリプトを変更します。
Is someone trying to say someone took some measurements
誰かが測定をしたと言いたいのだろうか
Then do some calculations say
次に、いくつかの計算をしてみましょう
How much force is needed to make the spicy hot
辛さを辛くするにはどれくらいの力が必要か
what happens to it after it's hot
暑くなった後はどうなりますか
So this is another thing that can be tuned
これは調整できる別のことです
So if you want to change its nature
したがって、その性質を変えたい場合は、
This is a mechanical method
これは機械的な方法です
can be changed
変更可能
The second question is why it is called Lingwei
2番目の質問は、なぜ霊威と呼ばれるかです。
i was from behind
私は後ろから来ました
For example, our three-dimensional space
たとえば、私たちの三次元空間
If you have a direction take it away
方向性があるならそれを取り去ってください
let it not let it confine you
あなたを閉じ込めないようにしましょう
We become two-dimensional actions
二次元のアクションになる
Like a face, this is two-dimensional
顔と同じで二次元です
It can move in two directions
2方向に移動できます
that becomes a line again
それはまた線になる
If this is the case, you actually need to snuggle because it
この場合は、実際に寄り添う必要があります。
This direction is completely free to move
この方向は完全に自由に移動できます
Then we don't consider the other side
そうすれば、相手のことは考えません
it won't come out
それは出ないだろう
That said, get it down like this
そうは言っても、このように降ろしてください
What do you call one when you search for me?
私を検索するとき、あなたは何と呼びますか？
In other words, this is called Lingwei
つまり、これを霊威といいます。
Because I can't move in every direction
全方向に動けないから
this is just a description
これは単なる説明です
It's not that what that spirit means
その精神が意味するものはそういうことではない
Just saying that every direction is restricted
全方向が制限されていると言うだけです
All directions are restricted
全方向が制限されています
so there's nothing left
だから何も残らない
There is no such degree of freedom left
そんな自由度は残っていない
So there was a speech like this
そこでこんな講演がありました
It's not that
そうではありませんが
so
それで
sorry
ごめん
because I'm not an undergraduate
私は学部生ではないので
i want to ask
聞きたいです
Since the previous ratio is also graphite
前回のレシオもグラファイトなので
Then that graphite west is graphite
じゃあそのグラファイト・ウェストはグラファイトだ
so i heard your speech till now
それで今まであなたのスピーチを聞いていました
it feels like saying
と言っているような気がする
graphite west so so good
グラファイトウェストとても良い
so precious
とても貴重です
simply because it can be a very thin layer
それは単に層が非常に薄い可能性があるためです
big piece
大きな部分
So our front ratio is many, many
つまり、我々のフロントレシオは非常に高いのです
Broken graphite west piled together
壊れた黒鉛を積み上げた西
OK
OK
It's not broken, it's a very regular arrangement
壊れてないよ、とても規則正しい配置だよ
right
右
you
あなた
In fact, if you spend so much together
実際、一緒にたくさん過ごしたら
it will automatically
それは自動的に行われます
line up because it is the lowest energy
一番エネルギーが低いから並ぶ
That graphite is what we go to the heart of thousands of miles
そのグラファイトは私たちが何千マイルも離れた中心部に行くものです
The distance between each layer
各層間の距離
Probably, this is less than one
おそらくこれは 1 未満です
Is a few of the collar three Answeron
3人のアンサーロンのリーダーです
That's 0.3 nanometers
それは0.3ナノメートルです
That means, you take one
つまり、1つを取るということです
then it lined up well
そしたらうまく並びました
Sometimes the direction is a little bit wrong, it doesn't matter
時々、方向が少し間違っていることもありますが、それは問題ではありません
But it's layer by layer, well piled up
でもそれは一層ずつ、しっかりと積み重なっている
not to say that standard
その標準とは言わない
Perfect like this, but roughly
このように完璧ですが、大まかに言うと
this direction, this is
この方向、これは
Do it perpendicular to this, there is no problem
これに対して垂直にやれば問題ありません
So what about its permutation?
したがって、その順列
you can imagine saying
こう言うのは想像できるだろう
that millimeter
そのミリメートル
Do you know how much a millimeter is
1ミリメートルが何ミリか知っていますか
It has about 3 million layers
約300万のレイヤーがあります
inside
中身
so so well lined up
とても並んでいます
So, usually you take a piece
それで、通常、あなたは一枚を取る
Take the heart of thousands of miles down, it's a big piece, a lot of piles
何千マイルも離れた心臓を取り出してみると、それは大きな部分であり、その多くは
didn't split it
分割しませんでした
because
なぜなら
Why did you say it was made this time?
なぜ今回作ったと言ったのでしょうか？
This is a pretty good situation
これはかなり良い状況です
Everyone wants to say take it apart
みんなが言いたいんだ、分解しろよ
It's not that I can't think of a good way to separate it
良い分離方法が思いつかないわけではない
Now there are still some chemical ways to separate it
現在でも化学的に分離する方法がいくつかある
That is to say, for example, if you bring graphite
つまり、たとえばグラファイトを持ってきた場合、
you put some other molecules in between
間に他の分子を入れると
Or nourish it
あるいは栄養を与える
Or put those things in OH to fill it up
またはそれらをOHに入れて埋めてください
then it swells
それから膨らみます
Yes, expand it and put it in agriculture
はい、拡張して農業に取り入れましょう
It strips off every layer and every layer
すべての層をすべて剥ぎ取ります
So this is also a method
ということで、これも方法です
chemical method
化学的方法
Because I still don't understand
まだ理解できないから
so ask
それで聞いてください
Since there are many layers
層が多いので
tell me if i ask a stupid question
愚かな質問をしたら言ってください
That is to say, it is layer by layer in nature
つまり、本質的には層ごとにあります
Is there no way to say their
彼らのことを言う方法はありませんか？
the edge of each layer
各層の端
Is there any way to connect them
それらを接続する方法はありますか
Because if we can find such a method
なぜなら、そのような方法を見つけることができれば、
not that they are cluttered inside the pencil
鉛筆の中に散らかっているわけではありません
we just break it up
私たちはそれを壊すだけです
Then each piece is connected
そして、それぞれのピースがつながっていきます
that's what we want
それが私たちが望んでいることです
so the problem is heavy
だから問題は重い
But the other is to say
しかし、もう一つはこう言うのです
Since there are diamonds in nature
ダイヤモンドは自然界に存在するので、
Diamonds are also hard to make
ダイヤモンドも作るのが難しい
Will there be graphite series in nature?
自然界に黒鉛系列は存在するのでしょうか?
Although we humans find it difficult to do
私たち人間にはそれが難しいと感じていても、
If nature had a way of forming it like this
自然がこのように形成する方法があったとしたら
maybe find out
もしかしたら分かるかもしれない
we don't have to think
私たちは考える必要はありません
right
右
OK, there are graphite series in nature
OK、自然界には黒鉛系列があります
Just say two pieces together
2つの部分を一緒に言うだけです
it will come together
それは一緒になるでしょう
because it usually interacts
普通にやり取りするから
Unless you have a layer of graphite
グラファイトの層がない限り
you are on a surface
あなたは表面上にいる
just stand over there other stuff
他のものはそこに立ってください
don't touch it
触らないでください
or how does it find
またはどうやって見つけますか
Now I mean, everyone think of a way to say
さて、みんながこう言う方法を考えたとします。
grow it in the lab
研究室で育ててください
it's heating or something
暖房か何かです
it grows naturally
それは自然に成長します
This is what everyone wants now
これは今誰もが望んでいることです
if nature
自然なら
It has been achieved that it can be naturally developed into a layer
自然にレイヤーに展開できることを実現しました
Then we humans can find this method
そうすれば、私たち人間はこの方法を見つけることができます
to develop it naturally into a layer
自然にレイヤーに発展させます
Because if many layers collide
多くの層が衝突すると
become graphite
グラファイトになる
Graphite is useless.
グラファイトは駄目だよ。
because it works later
後で効くから
it becomes it is a metal
それは金属になります
Then it just says less
そうすれば、発言が少なくなるだけです
some nice features
いくつかの素敵な機能
When you get to the first floor
1階に着いたら
some other features
その他の機能
will run out
足りなくなります
After interaction
インタラクション後
will offset these things
これらのものを相殺します
sorry
ごめん
i'll waste a little more time
もう少し時間を無駄にします
but you just said
でもあなたは今言った
A pencil is many small flakes of graphite
鉛筆は黒鉛の小さな片がたくさん集まったものです
'cause they suck together
だって彼らは一緒に吸うから
But every little piece
でも、どんな小さな部分も
It will always have a beginning from graphite to a small piece
始まりはいつも黒鉛から小さな破片まで
but how do you pick out
でもどうやって選ぶの？
you can't your fingers so single
指をそんなに一本にすることはできない
How would you pick out
どうやって選びますか
you have to have a very thin
非常に薄いものでなければなりません
something the size of a round paper
一個圓紙大小的東西
clip paper to clip it out
紙をクリップして切り抜きます
this is something we didn't do
これは私たちがやっていなかったことです
there is no way you have a round paper
丸い紙があるわけがない
The size of the paper clip to pick out this layer
このレイヤーを選択するためのクリップのサイズ
if it can be done
それができるなら
Just pick that layer out
そのレイヤーを選択するだけです
IPN seems to have AtomTrees
IPNにはAtomTreesがあるようです
Then I remember that in biochemistry
それから生化学のことを思い出しました
Seems like a technology called LaserTrees
LaserTreesという技術のようです
There is no way to pull a person like this
こんな人を引っ張るわけがない
that is to say already
つまりすでに
achieve a small degree of graphite west
少量のグラファイトウェストを実現
come out piece by piece
少しずつ出てくる
If you push the trash
ゴミを押し込めば
It is a
それは
it can move a large molecule
大きな分子を動かすことができる
The space is still quite large
スペースはまだかなり広いです
Graphite is an atom
グラファイトは原子です
So it could have the one with thousands of atoms
つまり、数千の原子を持つものがある可能性があります
that thing it can control it
それはそれを制御できるということ
push it move it
押して動かします
There is still a difference in scale
やはりスケールが違いますね
because
なぜなら
There is still a difference in scale, the one in nanometers
ナノメートル単位のスケールの差はまだある
you might imagine
あなたは想像するかもしれません
like nanometer
ナノメートルのような
Now it's what everyone says is the sharpest thing
今、それが最も鋭いものだと誰もが言うものです
Because a small such a small tube
細い管はとても小さいので、
That head is very sharp
その頭はとても鋭いです
so you use it for some other application
それで、それを他のアプリケーションに使用します
The so-called pointed one is its
いわゆる尖ったものは、
That circle is about a few nanometers
その円は数ナノメートル程度です
is in the nanometer range
ナノメートル範囲にあります
So presumably things will never be smaller than a nanometer again.
したがって、おそらく、物体が再び 1 ナノメートルより小さくなることはないだろう。
Because smaller than nanometer
ナノメートルより小さいので
you are about to enter the atom
あなたは原子に入ろうとしています
the size of an atom
原子の大きさ
is the distance between atoms
原子間の距離です
like this
このような
On the graphite side or in the graphite system
グラファイト側またはグラファイト系内
The distance between judgment and detection is 0.14 difficulty
判断と検出の距離は難易度0.14
That's probably the smallest distance
おそらくそれが最短距離です
right now we
今、私たちは
if you go again
また行ったら
It's probably going to go into that thing in the yard box.
おそらく庭の箱の中に入るでしょう。
So it's chemical
だから化学的だよ
We probably only had a few Ansejangs in mind
おそらくアンセジャンは数個しか念頭になかったでしょう
on this
これについて
There are plans mentioned in this major
このメジャーで言及されている計画があります
That is, the production of the West Rock Line has reached its physical limit.
つまり、ウエストロックラインの生産は物理的な限界に達しているのです。
The so-called physical limit
いわゆる物理的な限界
that is
あれは
How long will it take you and us to reach that limit now
あなたと私たちがその限界に達するまでにどれくらい時間がかかりますか
or we
または私たち
almost to the limit
ほぼ限界まで
But it is very difficult to reach this limit
しかし、この限界に達するのは非常に困難です
that could be a long time
それは長い時間になるかもしれない
Then everyone has a lot of spirituality
そうするとみんな精神性が豊かになってきますね
Then we look forward to having new materials to look forward to
それでは、新たな素材を楽しみにしています
ok my so-called limit
OK、私のいわゆる限界です
That is to say, you have a CPU
つまり、CPU を搭載しているということです。
How many legendary stones can be placed on the upper right
右上に伝説の石をいくつ置けるか
In the end let them now be two little
結局のところ、今は二人の小さなままにしておきます
One foot is very close
足がとても近い、とても近い
different in the middle
真ん中が違う
Like we put some Oxide MRT
Oxide MRT を置いたようなもの
Yes, that's already very, very thin
はい、それはすでにとてもとても薄いです
the limit is
限界は
you can't
できません
You are about a few percent thinner
数パーセントほど痩せています
After a few percent of the round paper
紙を丸めて数パーセントを経た後
you probably won't be able to go down
おそらく降りることはできないだろう
further down it will touch
さらに下では接触します
will affect each other
お互いに影響し合うだろう
so say something
だから何か言ってください
current design
現在的設計
to the current design
現在のデザインに
Then they probably in a certain situation
それから彼らはおそらく特定の状況にいます
no longer possible
もう不可能です
we can't put these things
私たちはこれらのものを置くことはできません
further increase
さらに増加する
that number for example
たとえばその数字
The current situation in 2010 now
2010年の現在の状況
maybe every one of you
たぶんあなた方全員が
When each transistor operates
各トランジスタが動作するとき
what a nice electron
なんて素敵な電子なんだろう
what a current
なんという電流だ
maybe it's time to say
たぶん言う時が来た
A dozen or twenty electrons went to operate
十数個か二十個の電子が動き始めた
so everything will come to an end
だからすべてが終わるだろう
go down like discreet
控えめに下がる
I say this because the way it's currently designed
私がこれを言っているのは、現在の設計方法だからです
The way everyone built the base to make it
みんなが拠点を築き、それを作り上げた方法
The purpose of finding new materials is to say
新しい材料を見つける目的は次のとおりです。
If the new material has better properties
新しい材料の特性が優れていれば
If it is more powerful
もっと強力なら
then we can say
それから私たちは言うことができます
Don't go as small as that will achieve the same function
同じ機能を実現するためにあまり小さくしないでください
That means doing it in another way.
つまり、別の方法で行うということです。
Then everyone's ballistic body over there
そしたらそこにいるみんなの弾道体
Everyone in the industry probably has a different view
業界の人はそれぞれ違う意見を持っているでしょう
that is to say you till now
つまり今までのあなたは
We now have a new CP coming out every year
今では毎年新しいCPが登場します
how long then
それからどれくらい
This is what is said in the past
昔はこう言われてた
about ten or fifteen years
10年か15年くらい
That has already reached the complete limit of physics.
それはすでに物理学の限界に達しています。
The limit means that two things will meet together and cannot
限界とは、2 つのものが一緒に接触するが、接触することはできないことを意味します。
multiple
多数
how much can you say
どれくらい言えますか
You have to have something to do with him
あなたは彼と何か関係があるはずです
How many atoms are related
いくつの原子が関係しているか
That's under several tens of atoms
それは数十原子以下です
He is still a semiconductor
彼はまだ半導体だ
Or he still has a Primarch
それとも彼はまだ族長を持っているのか
This is a space for discussion
ここは議論のためのスペースです
i mean that part
その部分を意味します
i think today was a really good talk
今日は本当に良い話だったと思う
Many friends participated
たくさんのお友達が参加してくれました
we learned a lot of new things
私たちはたくさんの新しいことを学びました
I'm an amateur at this
私はこれに関しては素人です
So I have nothing to contribute
だから私は何も貢献することがない
But 20 years ago there was a cartoon
でも20年前にこんな漫画がありました
It is said that the fastest speed for human beings to send letters in the future
将来人類が手紙を送信する速度が最速になると言われている
The picture above is delivered by helicopter to the door of the American cargo
上の写真はヘリコプターでアメリカの貨物の玄関まで配達されています
did not expect
予期しなかった
Then ran out an E-mail out
その後、電子メールが送信されました
Therefore, as the director said just now,
したがって、先ほど局長が申し上げましたように、
how to develop in the future
今後どのように発展していくのか
we do not know
我々は知りません
we will wait and see
様子を見てみましょう
ok we thank you zhou
わかりました、ありがとうございます、周